Hi, everyone. I'm Abby.
嗨，大家好。我是艾比。
If you weren't here last week,
如果你上周不在这里，
I'm the head TA of this course.
我是本课程的主任TA。
And this is the second [NOISE] of three lectures that I'm
这是我讲的三个讲座的第二个[NOISE]
going to be giving on RNNs and related topics.
将给出RNN和相关主题。
Okay. So, welcome to week four.
好的。所以，欢迎来到第四周。
Today, we're going to be learning about vanishing gradients,
今天，我们将学习消失的渐变，
and some more complex types of RNNs.
以及一些更复杂的RNN类型。
So, before we get started,
所以，在我们开始之前，
I've got a few announcements.
我有几个公告。
Uh, the first announcement is that assignment four is released today, uh,
呃，第一个宣布是今天发布了第四个任务，呃，
it's due Thursday of next week, not Tuesday,
它将在下周四，而不是周二，
so that means you have two days more to do it than you did for all the other homeworks.
所以这意味着你比其他所有作业都要多做两天。
And the reason for that is assignment four is
其原因是任务四是
probably more work than the other homework so far,
到目前为止，可能比其他作业更多的工作，
so don't be surprised by that.
所以不要对此感到惊讶。
Uh, assignment four is all about Neural Machine Translation.
呃，任务四是关于神经机器翻译。
Uh, we're gonna learn about NMT on Thursday's lecture this week.
呃，我们本周将在周四的讲座上了解NMT。
And, uh, this is really exciting,
而且，呃，这真的令人兴奋，
because actually CS 224 has never had an NMT assignment before,
因为CS 224之前从未进行过NMT任务，
so this is all new this year,
所以今年全新，
and you're gonna be the first year students who are going to be doing an NMT assignment.
你将成为第一年开始做NMT任务的学生。
Uh, something else that's different about
呃，其他一些不同的东西
assignment four is that you're going to be using Azure, which is, uh,
任务四是你将使用Azure，呃，
a cloud computing service,
云计算服务，
in order to train your NMT systems on a virtual machine with a GPU.
为了在具有GPU的虚拟机上训练您的NMT系统。
And, uh, this is necessary in order to be able to do it in a reasonable amount of time.
而且，呃，这是必要的，以便能够在合理的时间内完成。
So, I have a warning which is,
所以，我有一个警告，是，
if you're a person who perhaps doesn't have, ah,
如果你是一个可能没有的人啊，
learnt- a lot of experience working on remote machines,
学习 - 在远程机器上工作的很多经验，
so for example if you're not very familiar with SSH,
例如，如果你不熟悉SSH，
or tmux, or remote text editing,
或tmux，或远程文本编辑，
then I advise you to budget some extra time for assignment four,
然后我建议你预算一些额外的时间来完成作业四，
because that's probably gonna take you a little while to set up and get used to.
因为这可能需要你一段时间来设置并习惯。
So, again, I'm going to emphasize,
所以，我再次强调，
do get started early on assignment four, because, uh,
在任务四开始提前开始，因为，呃，
the NMT system takes about four hours to train on your virtual machine,
NMT系统需要大约四个小时来训练您的虚拟机，
so you really can't start it the night before and expect to get it in on time.
所以你真的无法在前一天晚上开始它并期望准时到达它。
Uh, and assignment four is really quite a lot more complicated than assignment three.
呃，任务四真的要比任务三复杂得多。
So, uh, don't get into a false sense of security if you found assignment three easy.
所以，呃，如果你发现任务很简单，就不要陷入虚假的安全感。
Um, so Thursday's slides on NMT are ready on the website today,
嗯，所以星期四在NMT的幻灯片今天在网站上准备好，
so you can even start looking at it today if you
如果你今天你甚至可以开始看它
want- if you wanna get started on assignment four early.
希望 - 如果你想早点开始任务四。
Uh, so, I have a few more announcements, uh,
呃，我还有几个公告，呃，
on the subject of projects, uh,
关于项目的主题，呃，
next week's lectures are going to be all about projects.
下周的讲座将全部与项目有关。
So, you're going to hear about, uh, question answering,
所以，你会听到，呃，回答问题，
and the default final projects,
和默认的最终项目，
and then you're also gonna get some tips about how you might,
然后你也会得到一些关于你怎么样的提示，
uh, choose and define your own custom projects.
呃，选择并定义自己的自定义项目。
So, it's fine if you're not thinking about a project this week, that's okay.
所以，如果你本周没有考虑一个项目，这很好，那没关系。
You can delay until next week to start thinking about it for the first time.
你可以推迟到下周开始第一次考虑它。
But if you are a person who is already thinking about your projects,
但如果你是一个已经考虑过你的项目的人，
for example, if you're trying to choose your custom projects, uh,
例如，如果您正在尝试选择自定义项目，呃，
then you should check out the website's project page,
那么你应该查看网站的项目页面，
because it has quite a lot of information about, uh,
因为它有很多关于的信息，呃，
how to choose your projects, and also some inspiration.
如何选择你的项目，还有一些灵感。
And that includes- we've collected some, uh,
这包括 - 我们收集了一些，呃，
project ideas from various members of the Stanford AI Lab.
来自斯坦福大学人工智能实验室各成员的项目创意。
So, these are faculty and PhD students and postdocs,
所以，这些是教师和博士生和博士后，
who have ideas for, uh,
谁有想法，呃，
NLP deep learning projects that they would like
他们想要的NLP深度学习项目
CS224n students such as yourself to work on.
CS224n等学生就像自己一样工作。
So, especially, if you're looking to maybe get into research later,
所以，特别是，如果你想在以后进行研究，
this is a really great opportunity, uh,
这是一个非常好的机会，呃，
to work with someone in the Stanford AI Lab,
与斯坦福大学人工智能实验室的人合作，
and maybe get some mentorship as well.
并且也许会获得一些指导。
Okay. So here's an overview.
好的。所以这是一个概述。
Uh, last week, we learned about Recurrent Neural Networks,
呃，上周，我们了解了回归神经网络，
um, we learned about why they're really great for Language Modeling.
嗯，我们了解了为什么他们真的非常适合语言建模。
And today, we're gonna learn about some problems with RNNs,
今天，我们将了解RNN的一些问题，
and we're gonna learn about how to fix them.
我们将学习如何修复它们。
And this is gonna motiva- motivate us to learn about some more complex RNN variants.
这将是动机 - 激励我们学习一些更复杂的RNN变种。
And then, uh, next lecture on Thursday,
然后，呃，周四的下一个讲座，
we're going to, uh, have some more application-based, uh, contents,
我们要去，呃，还有一些基于应用程序的内容，
so we are going to be learning about Neural Machine Translation,
所以我们将学习神经机器翻译，
which is a really important task in, uh,
这是一个非常重要的任务，呃，
NLP and deep learning, and in particular,
NLP和深度学习，特别是
we're gonna learn about this architecture called sequence-to-sequence with attention.
我们将要了解这种称为序列到序列的架构。
But in more detail,
但更详细地说，
today's lecture, uh, first,
今天的讲座，呃，第一，
we are going to learn about the vanishing gradient problem.
我们将了解消失的梯度问题。
And this is gonna motivate us to learn about two new types of
这将激励我们学习两种新类型
RNN called Long Short-Term Memory,
RNN称为长期短期记忆，
and Gated Recurrent Unit.
和门控经常性单位。
We're also going to learn about some other kind of
我们还将学习其他一些
miscellaneous fixes for the vanishing gradient problem,
对于消失的梯度问题的杂项修复，
or the exploding gradient problem.
或爆炸梯度问题。
Uh, so in particular,
呃，特别是，
we're going to learn about gradient clipping,
我们将学习渐变剪辑，
which is, uh, fairly simple, but quite important.
这是，呃，相当简单，但非常重要。
Uh, we're also going to learn about skip connections,
呃，我们也将学习跳过连接，
which is a fairly new neural architecture,
这是一个相当新的神经结构，
which tries to, uh,
试图，呃，
fix the vanishing gradient problem.
解决消失的梯度问题。
[NOISE] And then, at the end of the lecture,
[NOISE]然后，在讲座结束时，
we're gonna learn about some more fancy RNN variants such as, uh,
我们将学习一些更奇特的RNN变种，例如，呃，
bidirectional RN- RNNs, those are the ones which go not just left to right,
双向RN-RNN，那些不仅仅是从左到右的，
but also right to left,
而且从右到左，
and we're going to learn about multi-layer RNNs.
我们将学习多层RNN。
And that's when you stack multiple RNNs on top of each other.
那就是当你将多个RNN堆叠在一起时。
So, there's a lot of important definitions today.
所以，今天有很多重要的定义。
Um, so, you're gonna find that the information in
嗯，所以，你会发现信息
this lecture is pretty important for
这个讲座非常重要
assignment four and probably for your project as well.
任务四，也可能适用于您的项目。
Okay. So, let's get started thinking about the vanishing gradients.
好的。所以，让我们开始考虑消失的渐变。
Uh, so here we have an RNN,
呃，所以我们这里有一个RNN，
with, let say, ah, four steps,
用，啊，四步，
and suppose that we have some kind of loss that's, uh,
并假设我们有某种损失，呃，
J4, and that's computed based on the four hidden states.
J4，这是基于四个隐藏状态计算的。
So, let's suppose we're interested in asking what is the derivative of this loss J4,
那么，让我们假设我们有兴趣询问这种损失J4的衍生物，
with respect to the hidden states,
关于隐藏的状态，
uh, h1, the first hidden state?
呃，h1，第一个隐藏状态？
So, I'm representing that with this, uh,
所以，我代表那个，呃，
blue arrow notation to kind of represent how we have
蓝色箭头符号表示我们如何拥有
to make the gradients flow backwards in order to complete this.
使渐变向后流动以完成此操作。
So, if we're interested in what this gradient is,
所以，如果我们对这个渐变是什么感兴趣，
we can apply the chain rule and say, "Well,
我们可以应用连锁规则并说：“嗯，
it's the product of the, uh,
它是，呃的产物，
gradient of the loss with respect to h2,
相对于h2的损失梯度，
and then gradient of h2, with respect to h1."
然后是h2的梯度，相对于h1。“
And then, similarly, we can decompose that
然后，类似地，我们可以分解它
again using the chain rule, and we can do it again.
再次使用链规则，我们可以再做一次。
So, what we've done here is we've decomposed the gradient that we were interested in,
所以，我们在这里所做的是我们已经分解了我们感兴趣的渐变，
into the products of these various intermediate gradients.
进入这些各种中间梯度的产品。
And in particular, we're seeing all these ht by ht minus 1,
特别是，我们看到所有这些ht减去ht减去1，
uh, adjacent gradients of the hidden states.
呃，隐藏状态的相邻梯度。
So, the thing I want to ask you is,
那么，我想问你的是，
what happens if these gradients are small?
如果这些渐变很小会发生什么？
Given that there's a lot of them,
鉴于它们中有很多，
uh, what happens if they're small in magnitude?
呃，如果他们的规模很小，会发生什么？
So, the overall problem of the vanishing gradient problem,
那么，消失梯度问题的整体问题，
is that when these gradients are small,
当这些梯度很小时，
then our overall gradient is gonna get smaller and smaller,
然后我们的整体渐变会变得越来越小，
as it back propagates further.
因为它进一步传播。
Because the accumulated gradient is the product of all of these intermediate gradients.
因为累积梯度是所有这些中间梯度的乘积。
And when you multiply something by something small,
当你把东西乘以小东西时，
then the whole thing gets smaller.
然后整个事情变小了。
So, that's what I'm representing here with these, uh,
所以，这就是我在这里用这些代表的，呃，
smaller and smaller blue arrows going backwards.
越来越小的蓝色箭头向后。
So, that's the general idea of the vanishing gradient problem.
所以，这就是消失梯度问题的一般概念。
Here's a slightly more formal definition.
这是一个稍微更正式的定义。
So, if you remember from last time,
所以，如果你记得上次，
uh, if we have a null RNN,
呃，如果我们有一个无效的RNN，
then the hidden state ht is
然后隐藏的状态是
computed as a function of the previous hidden state ht minus 1,
计算为先前隐藏状态ht减1的函数，
and the current input xt.
和当前输入xt。
Uh, so you might remember in the previous lecture we
呃，所以你可能还记得在上一次演讲中我们
said that xt were one-hot vectors representing words,
说xt是代表单词的热门向量，
and then ET is the embedding.
然后ET是嵌入。
Uh, this lecture we're going to be,
呃，这个讲座我们会的，
uh, getting rid of that detail,
呃，摆脱那个细节，
and we're just gonna be thinking very abstractly about
而且我们只会非常抽象地思考
an RNN that has some kind of input xt,
一个有某种输入xt的RNN，
and xt is just any kind of vector.
和xt只是任何一种向量。
Probably a dense vector,
可能是一个密集的矢量，
but you know, it could be words or not.
但是你知道，这可能是文字与否。
It could be one-hot or dense.
它可能是一热的或密集的。
Uh, but that's just the input.
呃，但这只是输入。
So, that's the, uh,
所以，那就是，呃，
the definition that we learned last time for Vanilla RNNs.
我们上次为Vanilla RNN学习的定义。
So, this means that the derivative of ht,
所以，这意味着ht的衍生物，
hidden state on step t with respect to the previous hidden state,
相对于先前隐藏状态的步骤t的隐藏状态，
uh, is this expression here.
呃，这是这里的表达。
Uh, so this is just an application of the chain rule, and, uh,
呃，所以这只是链规则的应用，而且，呃，
if you looked long enough or refer back to
如果你看得够久或者回头看
the backprop lecture you'll see, uh, that that make sense.
你会看到的backprop讲座，呃，那是有道理的。
So, in particular, we're, um,
所以，特别是，我们是，嗯，
multiplying by Wh at the end, uh,
最后乘以Wh，呃，
because we have the multiplication of Wh and ht minus 1 on the inside.
因为我们在内部有Wh和ht减1的乘法。
Okay. So, if you remember, on the previous slide,
好的。所以，如果你还记得，在上一张幻灯片中，
we were thinking about what's the gradient of the loss on some step,
我们在考虑某些步骤的损失梯度是什么，
step i I'd say,
我会说，
with respect to a hidden state hj,
关于隐藏状态hj，
on some previous step j.
在前面的一些步骤j。
And maybe J is quite a few steps before i.
也许J在我之前还有很多步骤。
So, we can now write this,
所以，我们现在可以写这个，
uh, in the following way.
呃，用以下方式。
So just by applying the chain rule,
所以只要应用链规则，
now on the first line we're saying that this derivative that we're interested in
现在在第一行，我们说的是我们感兴趣的这种衍生物
can be decomposed into the derivative with respect to step i,
可以分解为关于步骤i的导数，
which is kind of the last step,
这是最后一步，
and then do all of those intermediate gradients of the adjacent hidden states as well.
然后也做相邻隐藏状态的所有中间梯度。
So, that- that first slide is just exactly the same thing as we were looking at on the,
那么，第一张幻灯片就像我们看到的那样完全一样，
uh, the picture, uh, the diagram on the previous slide.
呃，图片，呃，上一张幻灯片上的图表。
Okay. And then, given that we figured out what is, uh,
好的。然后，鉴于我们弄清楚是什么，呃，
dht by dht minus one,
dht减去一，
ah, further on the slide,
啊，进一步在幻灯片上，
then we can just substitute that in.
然后我们可以替换它。
So, what we're finding is that this overall gradient that we're
所以，我们发现的是我们的整体梯度
interested in, in particular,
特别感兴趣的是
has this term, uh,
有这个词，呃，
Wh, the weight matrix, and it's, uh,
Wh，重量矩阵，它是，呃，
multiplied by itself, i minus j times,
乘以它自己减去j次，
because there's i minus j many steps between, uh,
因为我之间有很多步骤，呃，
step j and step i,
步骤j和步骤i，
which is the- the distance that we're traveling with this gradient.
这是我们用这个梯度旅行的距离。
So, the big problem here is,
所以，这里的大问题是，
if this weight matrix Wh is small,
如果这个权重矩阵Wh很小，
then this term is gonna get vanishingly small,
然后这个词会变得非常小，
exponentially small, as i and j get further apart.
指数小，因为我和j进一步分开。
So, to give this a little more detail, uh,
那么，给这个更多细节，呃，
we can think about the, uh,
我们可以考虑一下，呃，
L2 matrix norms of all of these matrices, right?
所有这些矩阵的L2矩阵规范，对吗？
And, uh, as a- as a- uh, as a- sorry.
而且，呃，作为一个呃呀，抱歉。
I'm- it's a known fact of,
我 - 这是一个众所周知的事实，
uh, L2 norms that you have this, um,
呃，L2规范，你有这个，嗯，
inequality that's the, uh,
这是不平等，呃，
norm of the products of
产品规范
some matrices is less and equal to the product of the norms of the matrices.
一些矩阵小于和等于矩阵范数的乘积。
So, in particular, we're seeing that the norm of this gradient that we're interested in,
所以，特别是，我们看到了我们感兴趣的这种梯度的规范，
is less than or equal to, uh,
小于或等于，呃，
the product i minus j many times of the norm of the weight matrix Wh.
产品i减去重量矩阵Wh的范数的许多倍。
So, this is what we mean when we say we're concerned about Wh being small,
所以，当我们说我们担心Wh很小时，这就是我们的意思，
because if it's small, then the thing on the left has to be exponentially small.
因为如果它很小，那么左边的东西必须是指数小的。
So in particular in this,
特别是在这个，
uh, paper that, uh,
呃，纸，呃，
you can take a look at the bottom if you're interested, um, uh,
如果你有兴趣，你可以看看底部，嗯，呃，
Pascanu et al showed that if
Pascanu等人表明如果
the largest eigenvalue of the weight matrix Wh is less than one,
权重矩阵Wh的最大特征值小于1，
then this gradient on the left is going to shrink exponentially.
然后左边的这个渐变将呈指数缩小。
And you can probably see intuitively why this is true.
你可以直观地看到为什么这是真的。
So if, you know, as a simplifying assumption,
所以，如果你知道，作为一个简化的假设，
we suppose that Wh was not a matrix,
我们假设Wh不是矩阵，
but simply a scalar that was just a single number,
但只是一个只是一个数字的标量，
then you can see why if that number was greater than one,
然后你可以看到为什么如果这个数字大于1，
then the whole thing is gonna explode.
然后整件事就要爆炸了。
And if that number is less than one,
如果这个数字少于一个，
then it is going to shrink
然后它会缩小
exponentially as you multiply by the same number again and again.
当你一次又一次地乘以相同的数字时，指数地增加。
Uh, so you can check out the paper for more details,
呃，所以你可以查看论文了解更多细节，
but here, uh, the bound is one,
但在这里，呃，界限是一个，
partially because we have the sigmoid nonlinearity.
部分是因为我们有sigmoid非线性。
And that's, uh, based on the bounds of what we know as the,
那就是，呃，基于我们所知道的范围，
uh, norm of the sigmoid function to be.
呃，sigmoid函数的规范。
So, uh, this shows you why if the, uh,
所以，呃，这告诉你为什么，如果，呃，
Wh matrix is small,
Wh矩阵很小，
or if its largest eigenvalue was small,
或者如果它的最大特征值很小，
then we're going to have vanishing gradients.
然后我们将会消失渐变。
And similarly, if you check out the paper,
同样，如果你查看纸张，
you can see that there's a similar proof, uh,
你可以看到有类似的证据，呃，
relating if the largest eigenvalue is greater than one,
关联最大特征值是否大于1，
to having exploding gradients.
有爆炸的渐变。
So that's when the gradients get bigger and bigger,
所以当渐变越来越大时，
as you backprop further.
当你进一步支持。
Okay. So hopefully I've convinced you that
好的。所以希望我已经说服你了
vanishing gradients is a phenomenon that happens in our norms.
消失的梯度是我们的规范中发生的现象。
But I haven't yet said why this is a problem.
但我还没有说明为什么这是一个问题。
So, why should we view this as a bad thing,
那么，为什么我们认为这是一件坏事，
if the gradients are getting larger and larger,
如果渐变越来越大，
or smaller and smaller as you backprop?
或者越来越小，因为你支持？
So here's, uh, here's a picture that might illustrate why it's a bad thing.
所以这里，呃，这是一张图片，可以说明为什么这是一件坏事。
So, uh, as before,
所以，呃，和以前一样，
suppose that we're thinking about,
假设我们正在考虑，
what's the derivative of the loss on
什么是损失的衍生物
the fourth step with respect to the first hidden state?
关于第一个隐藏状态的第四步？
And we have this situation where
我们有这种情况
the gradient is getting smaller and smaller as it goes backwards.
随着向后倾斜，渐变越来越小。
But then, think about what is the gradient of let's say
但是，想想让我们说的渐变是什么
the loss in the second step also with respect to the first hidden state.
第二步中的损失也与第一隐藏状态有关。
So I'm representing that with the orange arrows.
所以我用橙色箭头代表那个。
And what my point is here,
我的观点是什么，
is that the magnitude of the gradient signal from close by,
是附近的梯度信号的幅度，
is a lot bigger than the magnitude of the gradient signal from far away.
远远大于远处梯度信号的幅度。
And this means that when you update your model weights,
这意味着当您更新模型权重时，
the signal that you're getting from close by is gonna
你要从附近得到的信号就是
be so much bigger than the signal from far away,
远远超过遥远的信号，
that essentially you're only going to learn,
基本上你只是要学习，
you're only going to optimize with respect to
你只是要优化
these nearby effects and not the long-term effects.
这些附近的影响，而不是长期影响。
So you're gonna, you're gonna lose the long-term effects, er, inside the,
所以你要去，你会失去长期的影响，呃，在里面，
the nearby effects. Any questions about this, yeah?
附近的影响。对此有任何疑问，是吗？
So, uh, where they say there that you do actual updates.
所以，呃，他们在那里说你做了实际的更新。
You know, there are actually some that are multiple chains, not just one chain.
你知道，实际上有一些是多链，而不仅仅是一条链。
So the nearer term should cover it.
因此，较近的术语应该涵盖它。
Sorry, what's the last part?
对不起，最后一部分是什么？
The nearer term should have a larger effect considering you're
考虑到你，较近的术语应该有更大的影响
updating the sum of the weights over different chains.
更新不同链上的权重总和。
Okay. So I think, ah, the observation was that,
好的。所以我想啊，观察的是，
given that, for example,
鉴于此，例如，
in Language Modeling you might be summing over multiple losses.
在语言模型中，您可能会在多个损失中进行总结。
There is a loss in every step and you sum all of them and that's your overall loss.
每一步都有一个损失，你总结所有这些，这就是你的整体损失。
Then you do want to update more with respect to the nearby losses than the far losses.
那么你确实希望更新更多关于附近的损失而不是远远的损失。
So I think, uh, yeah,
所以我想，呃，是的，
so if the design of your objective function
所以如果设计你的目标函数
is that it's the sum of the loss in every step,
是每一步中损失的总和，
then you do want to, uh,
那你确实想要，呃，
weight all of them equally.
所有这些都是平等的。
I think, uh, my point was more about,
我想，呃，我的观点更多，
what is the influence of, uh,
是什么影响，呃，
the action of the weight matrix at this early stage.
在这个早期阶段，权重矩阵的作用。
What is its influence on a loss that's nearby?
它对附近的损失有什么影响？
And what is its influence on a loss that's far away?
它对远在外的损失有何影响？
Um, and due to, uh,
嗯，由于，呃，
the dynamics of how the vanishing gradient, uh,
消失梯度的动态，呃，
problem works, then, uh,
问题有效，那么，呃，
the influence on the loss that's far away
对远方损失的影响
is gonna be much less than the influence nearby.
比附近的影响要小得多。
And I'm gonna give some more linguistics examples later of why you might want to learn,
我稍后会给你一些更多的语言学例子，说明你为什么要学习，
uh, the connections that are farther away.
呃，更远的连接。
So essentially the problem is,
基本上问题是，
in situations where you do want to learn the connection
在您确实想要学习连接的情况下
between something that happens early and something that happens later,
在早期发生的事情和稍后发生的事情之间，
then you're going to be unable to learn that connection.
然后你将无法学习这种联系。
Uh, so we'll see some motivating examples in a minute.
呃，所以我们会在一分钟内看到一些激励人心的例子。
Any other questions on this? Yeah?
还有其他问题吗？是吗？
Um, I'm getting confused like, why are you talking about like dh, dj dh.
嗯，我很困惑，为什么你要说像dh，dj dh。
Uh, it's like H parameter, like, are we going-
呃，就像H参数一样，我们要去 -
Yeah.
是啊。
from-
从-
Okay. That's a great question.
好的。这是一个很好的问题。
So you're asking why are we interested in some kind of dj by
所以你问我们为什么对某种dj感兴趣
dh given that we're not updating H. H is an activation not a weight.
dh，因为我们没有更新H.H是激活而不是重量。
Um, so the reason why we're thinking about that,
嗯，所以我们考虑的原因，
is because when you think about what is dj by dw,
是因为当你想到什么是dw dj时，
which is a thing that we're going to update.
这是我们要更新的事情。
That's always gonna be in terms of dj by dh at some point, right?
在某些时候，这总是以dj为单位，对吧？
So if we're thinking about W, you know,
所以如果我们考虑W，你知道，
and how it acts on, uh,
它是如何作用的，呃，
the transmission from h_1 to h_2,
从h_1到h_2的传输，
then dj4 by W in that position is going to have to go through dj4 by dh_2.
然后由W在那个位置的dj4将必须通过dh_2经过dj4。
So if we're getting vanishing gradients,
所以如果我们渐渐消失了渐变，
uh, as we back propagate further,
呃，当我们进一步传播时，
then it's kind of like a bottleneck.
那有点像瓶颈。
Then you're certainly going to have vanishing gradients as they affect, uh,
然后，你肯定会有影响消失的渐变，呃，
the recurrence matrix there,
那里的递归矩阵，
and indeed the matrix that's applied to the inputs.
实际上是应用于输入的矩阵。
Okay. I'm gonna move off now.
好的。我现在要离开了。
Uh, so another way to explain why vanishing gradients is a problem,
呃，另一种解释为什么消失梯度是一个问题的方法，
is you can think of it as, uh, a gradient.
你能想到它，呃，渐变。
You can think of it as a measure of the effect of the past on the future.
您可以将其视为过去对未来影响的衡量标准。
So we've already talked about this little bit.
所以我们已经谈过这一点了。
Uh, gradient is like saying, if I change, uh,
呃，渐变就像在说，如果我改变，呃，
this weight or this activation a little bit,
这个重量或这个激活一点点，
then how much and how does it affect this thing in the future.
那么它将来会对这件事产生多大影响？
So in particular, if our gradient is becoming vanishingly small over longer distances,
所以特别是，如果我们的渐变在较长的距离上变得越来越小，
let say from step T, step T to step T plus N,
让我们从步骤T，步骤T到步骤T加N，
then we can't tell whether in one of two situations.
那么我们无法判断是否存在两种情况之一。
So the first situation is maybe there's no dependency between
所以第一种情况可能是之间没有依赖关系
step T and step T plus N in the data.
步骤T和步骤T加数据中的N.
So perhaps we're learning on a task where,
所以也许我们正在学习一项任务，
in the task there truly is no collect, uh,
在任务中确实没有收集，呃，
connection or relationship to be
连接或关系
learned between what happens on step T and what happens on
了解在第T步发生的事情和发生的事情
step T plus N. So there truly is nothing to be
步骤T加N.所以真的没什么可做的
learned and it's actually correct that there should be,
学到了，实际上应该有，
you know, small gradients with respect to those two things.
你知道，关于这两件事的小渐变。
But the second possibility is that, yes,
但第二种可能性是，是的，
that is a true connection between those two things in the data and in the task.
这是数据和任务中这两件事之间的真正联系。
And really ideally we should be learning that connection.
理想情况下，我们应该学习这种联系。
Um, but we have the wrong parameters in our model to capture this thing,
嗯，但我们的模型中有错误的参数来捕获这个东西，
and therefore that is why the,
因此这就是为什么
the gradients are small.
渐变很小。
Because the model doesn't see them as connected.
因为模型没有看到它们是连接的。
So we are not learning the true dependency between these two things.
所以我们没有学习这两件事之间真正的依赖关系。
And the problem with the vanishing gradient problem is that it's,
消失梯度问题的问题在于，
we're unable to tell in this situation,
在这种情况下我们无法分辨
which of these two situations we're in.
我们所处的这两种情况中的哪一种。
Okay. So this is all pretty theoretical.
好的。所以这完全是理论上的。
I think this example should make it a little more,
我认为这个例子应该多一点，
more clear why the vanishing gradient problem is bad.
更清楚为什么消失的梯度问题是坏的。
So, uh, last week we learned about RNN-Language Models.
所以，呃，上周我们了解了RNN语言模型。
And if you remember Language Modeling is a task where you have some kind of
如果你还记得语言建模是一个你有某种特殊性的任务
text and then you're trying to predict what word should come next.
文本，然后你试图预测接下来会有什么词。
So, uh, here's a piece of text.
所以，呃，这是一段文字。
It says, um, ''When she tried to print her tickets,
它说，嗯，''当她试图打印她的票时，
she found that the printer was out of toner.
她发现打印机没有墨粉。
She went to the stationery store to buy more toner.
她去文具店买了更多的碳粉。
It was very overpriced.
这是非常高估的。
After installing the toner into the printer,
将墨粉安装到打印机后，
she finally printed her,'' and
她终于打印了她，'和
can someone shout out what word you think should come next?
有人会喊出你认为接下来应该出现的词吗？
Tickets.
门票。
Tickets. Yes, exactly.
门票。对，就是这样。
So that was easy for you to do because, uh,
这对你来说很容易，因为，呃，
it makes sense logically that if that was the thing she was trying to do,
从逻辑上讲，如果这是她想要做的事情，
that's the thing she's gonna do once she's gone the whole detour for the, for the toner.
对于碳粉而言，一旦她走完整个绕道，她就会做的事情。
Um, so the question is,
嗯，所以问题是，
can RNN-Language Models easily answer this question.
RNN-Language Models可以轻松回答这个问题。
Would they do well at this particular Language Modeling example?
他们会在这个特定的语言建模示例中做得好吗？
So for an RNN-Language Model to do well at this kind of example,
因此，对于RNN语言模型来说，在这种示例中做得很好，
then they need to learn from this kind of example in the Training Data.
然后他们需要从训练数据中的这种例子中学习。
So if it solves the example in the Training Data,
因此，如果它解决了训练数据中的示例，
then the RNN-Language Model will need to model the dependency.
那么RNN语言模型将需要对依赖关系进行建模。
Learn the connection between the appearance of
了解外观之间的联系
the word tickets early on on the 7th step,
在第7步早期的单词门票，
and the target word tickets at the end.
和最后的目标词票。
But if we have the vanishing gradient problem,
但如果我们有消失的梯度问题，
then these gradients, uh, if they know the step,
然后这些渐变，呃，如果他们知道这一步，
the, the last step with respect to the early step,
关于早期步骤的最后一步，
it's gonna be very small because it's,
它会非常小，因为它是，
it's a fairly long distance, right?
这是一个相当长的距离，对吗？
And this means that the model is going to be unable to
这意味着该模型将无法实现
learn this dependency, easily or at all.
轻松地或完全地学习这种依赖性。
So if the model can't learn this kind of dependency during training,
因此，如果模型在训练期间无法学习这种依赖性，
then the model is going to be unable to predict
然后模型将无法预测
similar kinds of long distance dependencies at test-time.
在测试时类似的各种长距离依赖。
Okay, here's another example.
好的，这是另一个例子。
Um, here's a piece of text.
嗯，这是一段文字。
Uh, the text says and this isn't a full sentence.
呃，文字说，这不是一个完整的句子。
This is just a partial sentence.
这只是一个部分句子。
It says, the writer of the books, blank.
它说，书的作者，空白。
And I'm gonna give you two options.
而且我会给你两个选择。
It's either, the writer of the books is or the writer of the books are.
它既可以是书籍的作者，也可以是书籍的作者。
So, uh, again shout out which one do you think it is, is or are?
所以，呃，再次喊出你认为它是哪一个，是或是？
Is.
是。
Is, that's right. So, uh, the correct answer,
是的，那是对的。所以，呃，正确答案，
a correct possible continuation of the sentence would be,
这句话的正确可能的继续是，
uh, the writer of the books is planning a sequel.
呃，这本书的作者正在策划一部续集。
I can't think of a continuation that goes the writer of the books are,
我想不出书籍作者的延续，
that would be, uh, grammatically correct.
那会是，呃，语法正确。
So the reason why I'm bringing up this example,
所以我提出这个例子的原因，
is because this shows a kind of tension between, uh,
是因为这显示出一种紧张关系，呃，
two things called, uh,
有两件事，呃，
syntactic recency and sem- uh, sequential recency.
句法新近度和顺序新近度。
So syntactic recency is the idea that in
因此，句法新近就是这样的想法
order to correctly predict the next word should be more is than are,
为了正确预测下一个单词应该是多于，
is that the word writer is the kind of syntactically close word here.
就是这个词作者是一种语法上比较接近的词。
So we say the writer of the books is because it's the writer is.
所以我们说这些书的作者是因为它是作家。
So you can see this as the word writer and is,
所以你可以把它看作是作家这个词，是的，
are, uh, syntactically close.
是，呃，语法上很接近。
Because if you looked at the dependency paths for example,
因为如果您查看依赖路径，例如，
then there would be a short path in that tree.
然后那棵树上会有一条短路。
So by contrast, se- sequential recency is the,
相比之下，连续的新近是，
uh, simpler concepts of how close words are just in the sentence as a sequence of words.
呃，关于单词在句子中作为一系列单词的简单概念的简单概念。
So in this example,
所以在这个例子中，
books and are, are very sequentially recent because they're right next to each other.
因为它们彼此相邻，所以书籍和它们是非常有序的。
So the reason I'm bringing this up is because,
所以我提出这个的原因是因为，
the second one would be incorrect but it's kind of a tempting option.
第二个是不正确的，但这是一个诱人的选择。
Because if you're mostly only paying attention to things that happened recently,
因为如果你大多只关注最近发生的事情，
um, then you might get distracted and think,
嗯，那么你可能会分心并思考，
"Oh, the books are, that sounds right."
“哦，这些书听起来是对的。”
So the problem here is that RNN-Language Models
所以这里的问题是RNN语言模型
are better at learning from sequential recency than sicta- syntactic recency.
在顺序新近度方面学习比在sicta-句法新近度方面更好。
And this is partially due,
这部分是由于，
due to the vanishing gradient problem.
由于消失的梯度问题。
Because especially perhaps, if your syntactically,
因为特别是，如果你的语法，
uh, related word is actually kind of far away,
呃，相关词实际上有点远，
then it might get really hard to use the information from the syntactically recent word,
然后可能会很难使用语法上最近的单词中的信息，
especially if there's a lot of strong signal from the sequentially recent word.
特别是如果顺序最近的单词中有很多强信号。
So, uh, there are some papers that show that RNN-Language Models make this kind of error,
那么，有些论文表明RNN语言模型会产生这种错误，
of saying are, rather than is.
说的是，而不是。
Uh, they make this kind of error more often than you would like, uh,
呃，他们比你想要的更经常犯这种错误，呃，
especially if you have multiple of these distracting words such as books, uh,
特别是如果你有多个这些分散注意力的词，比如书，呃，
in between, uh, the word you're trying to predict
介于两者之间，呃，你想要预测的那个词
and the true word that you should be, uh, referring to.
你应该说的真实的话，呃，指的是。
Okay, any questions on this? All right, moving on.
好的，对此有任何疑问吗？好的，继续前进。
So, we briefly mentioned that exploding gradients, uh, is a problem.
所以，我们简要地提到爆炸渐变，呃，是个问题。
So, I'm briefly going to justify why is exploding gradients a problem,
所以，我简单地说明为什么爆炸梯度成为问题，
and why does it, uh, what does it look like?
为什么呢，呃，它看起来像什么？
[NOISE] So, the reason why exploding gradients are a problem,
[NOISE]因此，爆炸渐变的原因是一个问题，
is if you remember this is how SGD works.
如果你还记得这是SGD的工作原理。
Uh, we say that the new parameters of the model,
呃，我们说模型的新参数，
which we represent by Theta,
我们由Theta代表，
is equal to the old premises,
等于旧房屋，
and then you take some step in the direction of
然后你朝着方向迈出了一步
negative gradients because you're trying to minimize the loss of J.
负梯度，因为你试图最小化J.的损失。
So, the problem is if your gradient gets really big, uh,
所以，问题是你的渐变真的很大，呃，
then your SGD update step is going to become really big too.
那么你的SGD更新步骤也将变得非常大。
So, you're going to be taking a very big step,
所以，你将迈出一大步，
and you're going to be drastically changing your model parameters, Theta.
而且你将彻底改变你的模型参数Theta。
And this means that you can end up with some bad updates.
这意味着你最终可能会遇到一些糟糕的更新。
We end up taking too large a step.
我们最终迈出了一大步。
And we're changing the parameters too much.
而且我们正在更改参数。
And this means that, uh,
这意味着，呃，
we kind of take a big step,
我们迈出了一大步，
and we end up in some, uh,
我们最终在某些，呃，
area where the parameters are actually very bad.
参数实际非常糟糕的区域。
Uh, with example the- for example,
呃，举例 - 例如，
they might have a much larger loss than they had before.
他们可能比以前有更大的损失。
So, in the worst case,
所以，在最坏的情况下，
this can often manifest as seeing, uh,
这常常表现为看，呃，
infinities or NaNs, not a number in your network when you're training it in practice.
无穷大或NaN，而不是您在实践中训练时网络中的数字。
[NOISE] So, this can happen because if you take such a big step
[噪音]所以，这可能发生，因为如果你迈出这么大的一步
that maybe you update your parameters so much that now they're infinity,
也许你更新你的参数，现在它们是无限的，
or minus infinity, something like that,
或者减去无穷大，就像那样，
then you're gonna have all of these infinities within your activations as well,
然后你也会在你的激活中拥有所有这些无限，
and then all of your losses are going to be infinity,
然后你所有的损失将是无限的，
and the whole thing just isn't going to work, at all.
而整个事情根本就不起作用了。
So, it's very annoying when this happens,
所以，当这种情况发生时非常烦人，
and unfortunately it happens, uh, fairly often.
不幸的是，它发生了，呃，经常发生。
And if it does then you have to essentially
如果它确实那么你必须基本上
restart training from some earlier checkpoint before you
在您之前从某些早期检查点重新开始训练
got the NaNs and the infinities because there's
得到NaNs和无穷大因为有
no kind of salvaging it from its new state.
没有任何一种从新的国家拯救它。
[NOISE] So, what's the solution to this exploding gradient problem?
[NOISE]那么，这个爆炸梯度问题的解决方案是什么？
[NOISE] Uh, the solution is actually pretty
[NOISE]呃，解决方案实际上很漂亮
simple and it's this technique called gradient clipping.
简单而且这种技术称为渐变剪裁。
So, the main idea of gradient clipping,
所以，渐变剪裁的主要思想，
[NOISE] is that if the norm of your gradient is
[NOISE]是你的渐变的标准是
greater than some threshold and the threshold is a hyperparameter that you choose.
大于某个阈值，阈值是您选择的超参数。
uh, then you want to scale down that gradient,
呃，那么你想缩小那个渐变，
um, before you apply the SGD update.
嗯，在你申请SGD更新之前。
So, the intuition is yo- you're still gonna take a step in the same direction.
所以，直觉就是哟 - 你仍然会向同一个方向迈出一步。
But you're gonna make sure that it's a smaller step.
但是你要确保这是一个较小的步骤。
[NOISE] So, here, um,
[NOISE]所以，在这里，嗯，
I've got a screenshot of some pseudocode from, uh,
我有一些假代码的屏幕截图，呃，
the related paper that, uh,
相关论文，呃，
proposed gradient clipping, or at least some version of gradient clipping.
建议的渐变剪辑，或至少某种版本的渐变剪辑。
[NOISE] And, um, it's pretty simple as you can see.
[噪音]而且，嗯，这很简单，你可以看到。
Uh, g hat is the vector which is the, uh,
呃，帽子是矢量，呃，
derivative of the error with respect to the premises,
关于房地的错误的衍生物，
and it's saying that if the norm of
它说的是，如果是规范的话
this gradient is greater than the threshold's, then you just scale it down.
这个渐变大于阈值，然后你只需缩小它。
But the important thing to note is that it's still pointing in the same direction,
但重要的是要注意它仍指向同一方向，
it's just a smaller step.
这只是一小步。
So, here's a picture to show how that might work out in practice.
所以，这是一张图片，展示了如何在实践中发挥作用。
And, uh, this is a diagram from the, uh,
而且，呃，这是一张图，呃，
deep learning textbook which is also linked on [NOISE] the website.
深度学习教科书，也链接在[NOISE]网站上。
So, what's going on here, is that, uh,
所以，这里发生的是，呃，
the picture here is the loss surface of a simple RNN.
这里的图片是简单RNN的丢失表面。
So, they made a very simple RNN that instead of having, uh,
所以，他们做了一个非常简单的RNN，而不是，呃，
a sequence of vectors as the hidden states,
一系列向量作为隐藏状态，
it just suppose that each hidden state is simply just a single scalar.
它只是假设每个隐藏状态只是一个标量。
So, this means that instead of having a weight matrix, w,
所以，这意味着，而不是有一个权重矩阵，w，
and the bias vector, b,
偏差矢量b，
you have a scalar w and a scalar b.
你有一个标量w和一个标量b。
So, that's why in the picture, you just have this like two-dimensional parameter space.
所以，这就是为什么在图片中，你就像二维参数空间一样。
And then the, the z-axis is your, is your loss.
然后，z轴是你的，是你的损失。
So here, high loss is,
所以在这里，高损失是，
is bad and low loss is good in what you're trying to get.
很糟糕，低损失对你想要得到的东西很好。
So, uh, here in this picture,
所以，呃，在这张照片中，
you've got this kind of cliff, right, where you have this very steep cliff face,
你有这样的悬崖，对，你有这个非常陡峭的悬崖面，
uh, where the loss changes very quickly.
呃，损失变化很快。
[NOISE] And this cliff is really dangerous because it has steep, steep gradients.
[NOISE]这个悬崖真的很危险，因为它有陡峭，陡峭的坡度。
And you might be in danger of taking a really big,
而且你可能会冒很大的危险，
[NOISE] uh, update step because you're on the area with a really steep gradient.
[NOISE]呃，更新一步，因为你在这个区域有一个非常陡峭的梯度。
[NOISE] So, on the left,
[NOISE]所以，在左边，
you've got a possible scenario of what might happen if you don't have gradient clipping.
如果你没有渐变裁剪，你可能会遇到可能发生的情况。
[NOISE] So, on the left, uh,
[NOISE]那么，在左边，呃，
you can see that you start kind of at the bottom of the cliff,
你可以看到你开始在悬崖的底部，
and you have a f- a si- a few small updates.
你有一个小的更新。
And then, in particular makes a bad update because you
然后，特别是因为你做了一个糟糕的更新
see there's a small kind of dip before it goes off the cliff.
看到它离开悬崖之前有一种小小的倾角。
So, th- the true local minimum,
那么，真正的局部最小值，
the optimal you're trying to get to is that the bottom of that small kind of ditch.
你试图达到的最佳状态是那个小沟的底部。
And, um, it starts off kind of near the edge of that ditch,
而且，嗯，它开始靠近那条沟的边缘，
and then there's a negative gradient going into it.
然后有一个负梯度进入它。
But unfortunately, the, the update kind of overshoots,
但不幸的是，更新类型的超调，
and it ends up going a long way off the cliff.
它最终离悬崖很远。
So now, it's in this bad situation where it's taken a bad update,
所以现在，正是在这种糟糕的情况下，这是一个糟糕的更新，
and now it's got a much bigger loss than it had [NOISE] before.
而现在它的损失比之前的[NOISE]大得多。
So now that it's on the cliff.
所以现在它就在悬崖上。
Again it, it measures the gradient,
再一次，它测量梯度，
and the gradient is very steep, right?
而且渐变很陡，对吧？
The gradient is very large.
渐变非常大。
So, when it takes a, uh,
所以，当需要时，呃，
update with respect to that gradient,
更新关于该渐变，
then because the gradient is so big,
然后因为渐变太大了
it takes a really huge step.
这需要迈出一大步。
And that's, um, the, the one to the right.
那是，嗯，是右边的那个。
You can see the step going to the right.
您可以看到右侧的步骤。
So, that's also a very bad update because it's just throwing
所以，这也是一个非常糟糕的更新，因为它只是投掷
it really far to some probably fairly random,
它真的很可能相当随机，
uh, configuration of w and b.
呃，w和b的配置。
So, on the left, you can see what can go wrong if you're taking
所以，在左边，你可以看到如果你正在服用会出现什么问题
these really big steps because you were in areas with a very steep gradient.
这些真正重要的步骤，因为你在陡峭的梯度区域。
So, by contrast on the right,
那么，相比之下，
you can see what might happen if you do have a gradient clipping.
你可以看到如果你有一个渐变剪裁可能会发生什么。
[NOISE] [NOISE] And, um, it's much less drastic, right?
[噪音] [噪音]而且，嗯，它不那么激烈吧？
You've got a similar kind of pattern where it takes a few steps into the ditch,
你有一个类似的模式，它需要几步进入沟渠，
and then ends up going off the cliff a little bit,
然后最终离开悬崖一点点，
but not too much because the gradient was clipped.
但不要太多，因为渐变被剪裁了。
And then, it's on the cliff and there's again a really steep gradient,
然后，它在悬崖上，又有一个非常陡峭的梯度，
but it doesn't take such a big step because again the gradient was clipped,
但它没有采取这么大的一步，因为再次修剪了渐变，
so that it kind of comes back down.
所以它有点回归。
So, you can see that plausibly by using this gradient clipping method,
所以，你可以通过使用这种渐变裁剪方法看到合理的，
you've got a, a kind of safer update rule,
你有一个更安全的更新规则，
where you're not gonna take any,
在哪里你不会采取任何，
any big crazy steps and you're more likely to kind of find the,
任何重大的疯狂步骤，你更有可能找到，
the true minimum which is at the bottom of the ditch.
在沟渠底部的真正最小值。
[NOISE] I think there was a question earlier.
[噪音]我认为之前有一个问题。
Was there a question over here? [NOISE]
这边有问题吗？ [噪声]
I just want to see the value. [NOISE] [NOISE]
我只是想看看它的价值。 [NOISE] [NOISE]
Okay. Anyone else?
好的。还有谁？
[NOISE]
[噪声]
Yeah?
是吗？
[NOISE] [inaudible]
[NOISE] [听不清]
So, the question is, in assignment three,
所以，问题是，在任务三中，
y- you saw the atom optimization algorithm which, uh,
你看过原子优化算法，呃，
has this thing called momentum,
有这个东西叫动量，
which essentially says that kind of like physical momentum in,
这基本上就像是一种体力，
in the real world, that if you've been traveling in the same direction for a while,
在现实世界中，如果你已经在同一个方向旅行了一段时间，
then you can take bigger steps,
然后你可以采取更大的步骤，
I think, and if you've recently kind of changed direction,
我想，如果你最近改变了方向，
then you should take smaller steps.
那么你应该采取更小的步骤。
And I think there's another element as well, where you divide by some factor.
而且我认为还有另一个因素，你可以用一些因素来划分。
[NOISE] So, it is a similar kind of idea.
[NOISE]所以，这是一种类似的想法。
I suppose it's a different criterion, right?
我想这是一个不同的标准，对吧？
So, what they both have in common is it's a kind of criterion for when to
所以，他们两者的共同之处在于它是什么时候的标准
scale up or scale down the size of your update step.
放大或缩小更新步骤的大小。
Um, and I think they're based on different notions
嗯，我认为他们是基于不同的观念
of when should you take bigger steps and when should you take smaller steps.
什么时候应该采取更大的步骤，什么时候应该采取更小的步骤。
When should you be cautious or less cautious?
你什么时候应该谨慎或不那么谨慎？
So, I guess here the criterion is different.
所以，我想这里的标准是不同的。
It's kind of a simple criterion saying, like if it's really steep,
这是一个简单的标准，如果它真的很陡，
then be careful. Yeah. Another question?
那小心点是啊。另一个问题？
Uh, so the [inaudible]. [NOISE]
呃，所以[音频不清晰]。 [噪声]
Okay. So the question is,
好的。所以问题是，
is this similar to regularization of some kind, right?
这类似于某种正规化，对吧？
So, I suppose, yeah, there is- there are some things in common.
所以，我想，是的，有一些共同点。
Say for, example, L2 regularization says that you want, for example,
举例来说，例如，L2正规化表示你想要
your weight matrices to have a small L2 norm, right?
你的权重矩阵有一个小的L2范数，对吗？
And the idea is that you're trying to prevent
而这个想法是你试图阻止
your model from over-fitting the data by, um,
你的模型过度拟合数据，嗯，
having some kind of constraint that says you have to keep your weights fairly simple,
有某种约束，说你必须保持你的重量相当简单，
that is keep them, you know, small.
那就是让他们保持小小。
So, I suppose the relationship is that here we're
所以，我想这就是我们在这里的关系
saying that we don't want the norm of the gradients to be too big.
说我们不希望渐变的规范太大。
Ah, I don't know if this is related to overfitting.
啊，我不知道这是否与过度拟合有关。
Um, I guess I have to think more carefully about that,
嗯，我想我必须仔细考虑一下，
but I guess it's a similar kind of constraint that you're placing.
但我想这是一种类似的约束，你要放置。
Okay. I'm gonna move on for now.
好的。我现在要继续前进。
Uh, so we've talked
呃，所以我们谈过了
about how you might fix the exploding gradient problem with gradient clipping,
关于如何使用渐变剪裁修复爆炸梯度问题，
but we haven't talked about how we might fix the vanishing gradient problem.
但我们还没有谈到如何解决消失的梯度问题。
So, um, to recap,
所以，嗯，回顾一下，
I think one way to characterize the problem with the- the vanishing gradients in RNNs is
我认为用RNN消除渐变来表征问题的一种方法是
that it's too difficult for the RNN to learn to preserve information over many timesteps.
RNN很难学会在很多时间内保存信息。
So, in our example with printing
所以，在我们的打印示例中
the tickets and re- remembering that it's the tickets that she wants to print,
门票并重新记住这是她想要打印的门票，
you could think of it as it's hard for the RNN language model to correctly
你可以想到它，因为RNN语言模型很难正确
predict tickets because in a way, it's too hard for the RNN language model to,
预测门票，因为在某种程度上，RNN语言模型太难了，
uh, learn to retain the tickets information and use it later.
呃，学会保留门票信息并在以后使用。
So, um, if you look at the equation
所以，嗯，如果你看一下这个等式
for vanilla RNNs and how we compute the hidden state, uh,
对于vanilla RNN以及我们如何计算隐藏状态，呃，
based on the previous hidden state and- and the inputs,
基于先前的隐藏状态和 - 和输入，
you can see that the hidden state is in a way constantly being rewritten.
你可以看到隐藏的状态不断被重写。
It's always computed based on these, uh,
它总是基于这些来计算，呃，
linear transformations and the,
线性变换和
you know, the non-linearity.
你知道，非线性。
So, it's not all that easy to
所以，这并不容易
preserve the information from one hidden state to the other,
将信息从一个隐藏状态保存到另一个隐藏状态，
in particular, because we are putting it through this non-linearity function.
特别是因为我们正在通过这种非线性函数。
So, this motivates us to ask what about an RNN with some kind of separate memory?
那么，这促使我们问一下具有某种独立记忆的RNN呢？
If we have some kind of separate place to store information that we want to use later,
如果我们有一些单独的地方来存储我们想要在以后使用的信息，
then would this make it easier for our RNN
那么这会让我们的RNN变得更容易
to learn to preserve information over many timesteps?
学习如何在很多时间内保存信息？
So, this is the motivating idea behind LSTMs or Long Short-Term Memory RNNs.
因此，这是LSTM或长短期内存RNN背后的激励理念。
So, the idea here is that an LSTM is a type of RNN and it was proposed back in, uh, 1997.
因此，这里的想法是LSTM是一种RNN，并且在1997年提出了它。
And the idea is that this is, uh,
而这个想法就是，呃，
this was proposed as an explicit solution to the vanishing gradients problem.
这被提议作为消失梯度问题的明确解决方案。
[NOISE] So, one of the main differences here is
[NOISE]因此，这里的主要区别之一是
that on each step T instead of just having a hidden state h_t,
在每个步骤T而不是只有隐藏状态h_t，
we have both the hidden state h_t and the cell state which we denote c_t.
我们有隐藏状态h_t和我们表示c_t的单元格状态。
And both of these are vectors of some same length,
这两个都是长度相同的矢量，
n, and the idea there is that the cell is meant to
n，并且有一个想法是细胞的意思
sto- store our long-term information that, that's on memory units.
存储我们的长期信息，即存储单元。
Another super important thing is that the LSTM can
另一个非常重要的事情是LSTM可以
erase and write [NOISE] and read information from the cell.
擦除并写入[NOISE]并从单元格中读取信息。
So, you kind of think of this a bit like memory in a computer,
所以，你有点想到这有点像计算机中的内存，
in that you can do these operations, reading and writing and erasing,
因为你可以做这些操作，阅读，写作和擦除，
um, and that's how you're gonna keep your information.
嗯，这就是你要保留信息的方式。
[NOISE].
[噪声]。
Another super important thing is that the way the LSTM decides,
另一个非常重要的事情是LSTM决定的方式，
whether it wants to erase, write, read,
是否要擦除，写入，读取，
information and decide how much and which information,
信息并决定多少和哪些信息，
uh, that's all controlled by these [NOISE] gates.
呃，这些都是由这些[NOISE]门控制的。
So, the idea is [NOISE] that the gates are themselves also vectors of length n,
所以，这个想法是[NOISE]，门本身也是长度为n的向量，
and the idea there is that on each timestep,
并且每个时间步都有这个想法，
each element of these gates which are vectors are somewhere between zero and one.
这些门的每个元素都是矢量，介于0和1之间。
So here, uh, one represents an open gate and zero represents a closed gate,
所以在这里，呃，一个代表一个开放的门，零代表一个封闭的门，
and you can have values anywhere in between.
你可以在两者之间的任何地方拥有价值。
So, the overall idea, which we're gonna firm up on the next slide,
那么，整体想法，我们将在下一张幻灯片中坚定，
but the overall idea is that if the gate is open,
但总的想法是，如果大门打开，
that represents some kind of information being passed through,
代表某种传递的信息，
and if the gate is closed,
如果门关闭，
it [NOISE] means that information does not pass through.
它[NOISE]意味着信息不会通过。
Okay. So, the last really important thing is that the gates are dynamic.
好的。所以，最后一个非常重要的事情是门是动态的。
They're not just set at some constant value for the whole sequence.
它们不仅仅是为整个序列设置了一些恒定值。
[NOISE] Um, they're dynamic,
[NOISE]嗯，他们很有活力，
which means that they're different on each timestep T,
这意味着它们在每个时间步长T上都不同，
and the value that is the decision of whether they're open or closed and in which ways,
以及决定它们是开放还是关闭以及以何种方式决定的价值，
[NOISE] um, that is computed based on the current context.
[NOISE]嗯，这是根据当前的上下文计算的。
Okay. So here's, um,
好的。所以这是，嗯，
here's the- the equations for the LSTM which might make it clearer.
这里是LSTM的方程式，可能会让它更清晰。
So, uh, suppose we have some sequence of i- inputs x_t and we
所以，呃，假设我们有一些i-输入序列x_t和我们
want to compute a sequence of hidden state h_t and cell states c_t.
想要计算一系列隐藏状态h_t和单元状态c_t。
So, this is what happens on timestep t. Uh,
所以，这就是在时间步长t上发生的事情。呃，
this process equation shows you the three gates that I talked about before.
这个过程等式向您展示了我之前谈过的三个门。
So, the first one is called the Forget Gates.
所以，第一个被称为忘记盖茨。
And the idea is that this one is controlling what is kept versus what is forgotten,
而这个想法是，这个是控制什么保持与被遗忘的，
um, from the previous cell state, the previous memory.
嗯，从前一个单元状态，前一个内存。
And you can see that this forget gate is computed based on, uh,
你可以看到这个遗忘门是根据呃计算的，呃，
the previous hidden state h_t minus one and the current input x_t.
先前隐藏状态h_t减去1并且当前输入x_t。
Um, so that's what I meant when I said that it's
嗯，这就是我说的时候我的意思
dynamic and it's computed based on the- the current context.
动态，它是基于当前上下文计算的。
[NOISE] Um, you can also see that it's computed using,
[NOISE]嗯，你也可以看到它是用计算的，
uh, the sigmoid function,
呃，sigmoid函数，
which means that it is somewhere between zero and one.
这意味着它介于0和1之间。
Okay. The next gate is called the input gate,
好的。下一个门称为输入门，
and this one controls what parts of the new cell contents are written to the cell.
并且这个控制新单元格内容的哪些部分被写入单元格。
So, the idea there is that you have this- this memory cell and this is kind of, um,
所以，有这个想法就是你有这个 - 这个记忆细胞，这是一种，嗯，
controlling like ho- how and what you get to write to the memory cell.
控制如何以及如何写入存储单元。
Okay. And the last one is called the upper gate.
好的。最后一个被称为上门。
So, this one is controlling, uh,
所以，这个是控制，呃，
what parts of the cell are outputs to the hidden state,
单元格的哪些部分输出到隐藏状态，
[NOISE] so you could view this as kind of like the read function, right?
[NOISE]所以你可以把它看作有点读功能吧？
We're going to read some information from
我们将从中读取一些信息
our memory cell and that's gonna get put into our hidden states,
我们的记忆细胞，这将被置于我们隐藏的状态，
and this gate is gonna control that.
而这个门将控制它。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
[NOISE] Uh, yeah, that's just the sigmoid function as we noted before.
[NOISE]呃，是的，这只是我们之前提到过的S形函数。
All right. So, the next set of equation shows how we use these gates.
行。因此，下一组方程式显示了我们如何使用这些门。
[NOISE] So, the first line, uh,
[NOISE]那么，第一行，呃，
you could regard this, uh,
你可以这么看，呃，
c_tilde as the new [NOISE] cell content.
c_tilde作为新的[NOISE]单元格内容。
So, uh, this is the new content that you want to write to the cell,
所以，呃，这是你要写入单元格的新内容，
[NOISE] and this is also computed based on, uh,
[NOISE]，这也是基于，呃，
your previous hidden state and your current inputs,
您以前的隐藏状态和当前输入，
and this goes through your tan h non-linearity.
这经历了你的非线性。
So, uh, this is kind of the- the main contents that
所以，呃，这是主要的内容
you are computing based on the context and you want to write this into memory.
您正在根据上下文进行计算，并且您希望将其写入内存。
So, on the next line what's happening is that we're going to use
所以，在下一行，我们将要使用的是正在发生的事情
the forget gate to selectively forget some of the information from the previous,
忘记门有选择地忘记了以前的一些信息，
[NOISE] uh, memory cell.
[NOISE]呃，记忆细胞。
And you can see that we're doing these element-wise products,
你可以看到我们正在做这些基于元素的产品，
that's what the little circle is.
这就是小圈子。
So, the idea is that if you remember that f_t is
所以，这个想法是，如果你记得f_t是
a vector full of values between zero and one,
一个充满0到1之间值的向量，
when you do an element-wise product between f_t and
当你在f_t和。之间做一个元素方面的产品时
the previous cell state c_t minus one,
前一个单元格状态c_t减一，
then what you're essentially doing is you're kind of masking
然后你真正在做的是你有点掩饰
out some of the information from the previous hidden state.
从之前的隐藏状态中输出一些信息。
Sorry, no. Previous cell state.
抱歉，没有。以前的细胞状态。
So, when f is one,
所以，当f是1时，
then you're copying over the information,
然后你要复制信息，
but when f is zero, then you're getting rid of that information,
但是当f为零时，你就会摆脱这些信息，
you are erasing it or forgetting it.
你正在删除它或忘记它。
Okay. And then the other half of this equation,
好的。然后是这个等式的另一半，
um, i_t times c tilde t, uh,
嗯，我知道了，呃，
that's the input gate controlling
这是输入门控制
which parts of the new cell contents are gonna get written,
新单元格内容的哪些部分将被写入，
written to the, to the cell.
写到了电池。
Okay. And then the last thing we do is we, uh,
好的。然后我们做的最后一件事就是我们，呃，
pass the cell through a tan h,
让细胞通过棕褐色，
that's just adding another non-linearity,
这只是增加了另一种非线性，
and then you pass that through
然后你通过了
the output gates and that gives you [NOISE] the hidden state.
输出门，给你[NOISE]隐藏状态。
So, in LSTMs, we often think of the hidden states as being,
因此，在LSTM中，我们经常将隐藏状态视为存在，
uh, like the outputs of the RNN.
呃，就像RNN的输出一样。
And the reason for this is that you kind of view
这样做的原因是你有点看法
the cell states as being this kind of
细胞就是这种状态
internal memory that's not generally accessible to the outside,
内部通常无法访问的内存，
but the hidden states are the parts that you're
但隐藏的状态是你的部分
gonna pa- pass on to the next part of the model.
将转到模型的下一部分。
So, that's why we view it as kind of like the output of the model.
所以，这就是为什么我们认为它有点像模型的输出。
[NOISE] Uh, and this is, yeah,
[NOISE]呃，这是，是的，
x just to remind the- there is- circles are
x只是为了提醒 - 有圆圈
element-wise products and that's how we apply the gates.
元素产品，这就是我们应用大门的方式。
Uh, did anyone have any questions about this?
呃，有没有人对此有任何疑问？
[NOISE].
[噪声]。
Okay. [NOISE] Um, so as a reminder,
好的。 [NOISE]嗯，这是一个提醒，
all of these are vectors of some same length n.
所有这些都是长度相同的向量n。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
So, some people learn better from diagrams than equations,
所以，有些人从图表而不是方程式中学得更好，
and here's a diagram presentation of the same idea.
这是一个相同想法的图表。
So, this is a really nice diagram from a blog post,
所以，这是博客文章中非常好的图表，
uh, by Chris Olah about LSTMs,
呃，Chris Olah关于LSTMs，
and that was a good place to start if you want to
如果你愿意，这是一个很好的起点
get an intuitive understanding of what LSTMs are.
直观地了解LSTM是什么。
So, in this diagram, uh,
那么，在这个图中，呃，
the green boxes represent timesteps,
绿色框表示时间步长，
um, and let's zoom in on the middle one and see what's happening here.
嗯，让我们放大中间的一个，看看这里发生了什么。
So, within one timestep,
所以，在一个时间步，
you can see that this diagram is showing exactly the same thing as
你可以看到这个图表显示的完全相同
those six equations showed on the previous slide.
在上一张幻灯片中显示了这六个等式。
So, uh, the first thing we do is we use the, uh, the current input x_t,
所以，呃，我们做的第一件事就是使用当前输入x_t，呃，
which is at the bottom and the previous hidden state h_t minus the one on the left,
它位于底部，前一个隐藏状态h_t减去左边一个，
and we can use that to compute the forget gate.
我们可以用它来计算遗忘门。
[NOISE] And you can see f_t is on that arrow there.
[NOISE]你可以看到f_t在那个箭头上。
And then you apply the forget gate to the previous, uh, cell,
然后你将遗忘门应用到前一个，呃，单元格，
and that's the same thing as forgetting some of the- the cell content from last time.
这与忘记上次的一些细胞内容是一回事。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
And then after that, you can compute the input gate, uh,
然后，你可以计算输入门，呃，
and that's computed in much the same way as the forget gate.
并且这与忘记门的计算方式大致相同。
And then you use the input gate to decide which parts of this,
然后你使用输入门来决定这个部分，
uh, new cell content get written to the cell,
呃，新细胞内容被写入细胞，
and that gives you the cell c_t.
这会给你单元格c_t。
So, here you can see that you computed the impu ga- input gates and
所以，在这里你可以看到你计算了impu ga-输入门和
the new content and then you use that to gate that and write it to the cell.
新内容，然后你用它来控制并将其写入单元格。
So, now we've got our new cell c_t,
那么，现在我们有了新的细胞c_t，
and then the last things we need to do is to compute our new output gate, that's o_t.
然后我们需要做的最后一件事是计算我们的新输出门，即o_t。
And then lastly, use the output gate to select which parts of
最后，使用输出门选择哪个部分
the cell contents you're gonna read and put in the new hidden state h_t.
您要读取的单元格内容并将其置于新的隐藏状态h_t。
So, that's, that's, uh, that's
那就是，那就是，呃，就是这样
the same thing as the equations we saw on the previous slide.
与我们在上一张幻灯片中看到的方程式相同。
Okay. So, that's LSTMs.
好的。那么，这就是LSTM。
Um, is there a question?
嗯，有问题吗？
What's the importance [NOISE]  [inaudible]
什么是重要[NOISE] [听不清]
The question is, why are we applying a tan h
问题是，为什么我们应用tan h
on the very last equation on this, on this slide?
关于这个的最后一个等式，在这张幻灯片上？
Why we're planning a tan h to the cell before applying the output gate?
为什么我们在应用输出门之前计划对单元格进行调整？
Let's see. Um.
让我们来看看。嗯。
Yeah. So, your question is, the- the cell,
是啊。所以，你的问题是，细胞，
the new cell content already went through a tan h. Um, I'm not sure.
新的细胞内容已经过了一段时间。嗯，我不确定。
So, I suppose a- a- a general answer is that it must
所以，我想一个普遍的答案就是它必须
be giving some kind of more expressivity in some way,
以某种方式给予某种更多的表现力，
and that it's not just applying
并且它不仅仅是应用
tan h's sequentially because you do have the gates in between.
tan h是顺序的，因为你确实有两个门。
Um, so I suppose there must be a reason,
嗯，所以我想必须有一个理由，
kind of similarly to when you apply- apply
与申请时类似
a linear layer you won't have a non-linearity before the next linear layer.
线性图层在下一个线性图层之前不会具有非线性。
I suppose maybe we're viewing these cases as a kind of linear layer?
我想也许我们将这些案例视为一种线性层？
I'm not sure. I'll look it up.
我不确定。我会查一查。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
So, uh, that's LSTMs.
所以，呃，那是LSTM。
And, um, re- if you recall,
而且，嗯，如果你还记得，
we were- oh, question?
我们是 - 哦，问题？
Yeah. Why is it that in the forget gate,
是啊。为什么在遗忘之门，
you don't look at the previous cell state but you just look at the new hidden state?
你不看前一个单元状态，但你只看新的隐藏状态？
Like it seems like if you're this- instead of
就好像你是这样 - 而不是
deciding what to forget from the cell state, you should look at it.
决定从细胞状态中忘记什么，你应该看看它。
So the question is, why is the forget gate
所以问题是，为什么忘记门
computed only for the previous hidden state and the current input,
仅针对先前隐藏状态和当前输入计算，
why is it not computed based on ct minus one itself, right?
为什么它不是基于ct减去一个本身计算的，对吧？
Because surely you want to look at the thing to figure
因为你肯定想看看要想的东西
out whether you want to forget it or not?
你是否想忘记它？
Um, that's a pretty good question.
嗯，这是一个非常好的问题。
Uh, so, I suppose one reason why you might think that this- this works fine is that
呃，所以，我想你可能认为这个 - 这个工作得很好的一个原因就是这个
the LSTM might be learning a general algorithm
LSTM可能正在学习一般算法
for where it stores different types of information in the cell, right?
它在哪里存储不同类型的信息，对吧？
So, maybe it's learning that in this particular position in the cell,
所以，也许它正在学习在单元格中的这个特定位置，
I learn information about this particular semantic thing and then in this situation,
我学习有关这个特定语义的信息，然后在这种情况下，
I want to use that or not use that, forget it or keep it.
我想使用它或不使用它，忘记它或保留它。
But, yeah, I haven't entirely convinced myself why you don't want to
但是，是的，我还没有完全相信自己为什么不想这样做
look at the contents of the cell itself in order to decide.
看一下细胞本身的内容以便决定。
I suppose another thing to notice is that ht minus one was read from ct minus one.
我想另一件事需要注意的是，从ct减1来读取ht减去1。
So, I suppose there is some information there but not necessarily all of the information.
所以，我想那里有一些信息，但不一定是所有的信息。
Ah, yeah.
啊，是的
I'm not sure, that's another thing I need to look up I guess.
我不确定，这是我需要抬头的另一件事我想。
[NOISE] Any other questions?
[NOISE]还有其他问题吗？
Okay. Ah, so, that's LSTMs and,
好的。啊，那就是LSTMs，
um, LSTMs were introduced to try to solve the vanishing gradient problem.
嗯，引入LSTM试图解决消失的梯度问题。
So, the question is, ah,
那么，问题是啊，
how exactly is this architecture making the vanishing gradient problem any better?
这个架构究竟是如何使消失梯度问题更好的？
So, you could, ah, see that the LSTM architecture
那么，你可以啊，看看LSTM架构
actually makes it easier for RNNs to preserve information over many time steps.
实际上，RNN更容易在很多时间步骤中保存信息。
So, while it w as kind of difficult for
所以，尽管它很难
the vanilla RNN to preserve the information over all of the hidden states,
vanilla RNN保存所有隐藏状态的信息，
there's actually a fairly easy strategy that makes
这实际上是一个相当简单的策略
it simple for the LSTM to preserve the information.
LSTM很容易保存信息。
So, namely, if the forget gate is set to remember everything on every step, um,
那么，如果忘记门被设置为记住每一步的一切，嗯，
that's a fairly simple strategy that will ensure that
这是一个相当简单的策略，可以确保这一点
the information in the cell is going to be preserved indefinitely over many time steps.
单元格中的信息将在许多时间步骤中无限期地保留。
So, I don't know if that's actually a good strategy for whatever task you're trying to do,
所以，我不知道这对你正在尝试做的任何事情来说实际上是一个好策略，
but my point is that there is at least, um,
但我的观点是，至少有，嗯，
a fairly straightforward way for the LSTM to keep the information over many steps.
LSTM通过多个步骤保持信息的一种相当简单的方法。
And as we noted that's relatively harder for the vanilla RNN to do.
正如我们所指出的那样，香草RNN相对难以做到。
So, you can think of this as the key reason why LSTMs are more able,
因此，您可以将此视为LSTM更有能力的关键原因，
ah, to preserve the information
啊，保存信息
and thus are more robust to the vanishing gradient problem.
因此对于消失的梯度问题更加稳健。
Ah, however, I think you should still know that LSTMs don't
啊，但是，我认为你应该知道LSTM不会
necessarily guarantee that we don't have a vanishing or exploding gradient problem.
必然保证我们没有消失或爆炸的梯度问题。
You could still have that problem,
你仍然可以遇到这个问题，
but the thing to remember is that it's easier to avoid it anyway.
但要记住的是，无论如何要避免它更容易。
Okay. So, um, LSTMs, ah,
好的。那么，嗯，LSTM，啊，
have been shown to be more robust to the vanishing gradient problem,
已被证明对消失的梯度问题更加稳健，
ah but I'm going to tell you a little about how they've
啊，但我会告诉你一些他们的情况
actually been more successful in real life. You have a question?
实际上在现实生活中更成功。你有问题吗？
Yeah,  [inaudible]
是的，[音频不清晰]
Okay. So it's a great question.
好的。所以这是一个很好的问题。
The question is, why is it that just because you
问题是，为什么只是因为你
have these LSTM defined forward equations,
有这些LSTM定义的正演方程，
why do you not have the vanishing gradient problem?
为什么你没有消失的梯度问题？
Why does the- the logic about, ah,
为什么 - 这个逻辑啊，
the chain rule kind of getting smaller and smaller or bigger and bigger not apply?
链规则越来越小或越来越大不适用？
So, I think the key here is that, um,
所以，我认为这里的关键是，嗯，
in the vanilla RNN,
在香草RNN中，
the hidden states are kind of like a bottleneck, right?
隐藏的状态有点像瓶颈，对吧？
Like all gradients must pass through them.
像所有渐变必须通过它们。
So, if that gradient is small then,
那么，如果那个渐变很小那么，
all downstream gradients will be small,
所有下游梯度都很小，
whereas here you could regard the cell as being kind of like
而在这里你可以认为细胞有点像
a shortcut connection at least in
至少在...中的快捷方式连接
the case where the forget gate is set to remember things,
忘记门被设置为记住事物的情况，
um, then that's kind of like a shortcut connection where
嗯，那就像是一个快捷连接
the cell will stay the same if you have the forget gate set to remember things.
如果你设置忘记门来记住事物，那么单元格将保持不变。
So, if the cell is staying mostly the same,
所以，如果细胞大部分保持不变，
then you are not going to be,
然后你不会，
ah, having the vanishing gradient via the cell.
啊，通过细胞消失梯度。
So, that means that to get a connection from
所以，这意味着从中获取连接
the gradient of something in the future with respect to something in the past,
关于过去的事情，未来某种事物的梯度，
there is a potential route for the gradient to
梯度有一条潜在的路径
go via the cell that doesn't necessarily vanish.
经过不一定消失的细胞。
So in that, I have one more question.
所以，我还有一个问题。
Um-uh.
嗯，嗯。
Since we have a shortcut [inaudible]
既然我们有捷径[听不清]
So I think the question was how do you check that your gradients are correct given that
所以我认为问题是你如何检查你的渐变是否正确
there are now multiple routes for information to travel?
现在有多条信息旅行路线？
Right.
对。
So, I suppose this somewhat relates to what we talked about last time with
所以，我认为这与我们上次谈到的内容有些关系
the multivariable chain rule about what is
什么是多变量链规则
the derivative of the loss with respect to a repeated weight matrix and we saw that,
关于重复权重矩阵的损失的导数我们看到了，
if there are multiple routes then
如果有多条路线那么
the multivariable chain rule says that you add up the gradients.
多变量链规则表示你加上渐变。
So, if your question is how do you do the calculus correctly and make sure it's correct,
那么，如果您的问题是如何正确地进行微积分并确保它是正确的，
I guess you just kind of apply
我想你只是申请
the multi-variable chain rule and it's more
多变量链规则，它更多
complicated than assessing with the LSTMs.
比评估LSTM更复杂。
Ah if you're using PyTorch 14 you do not have to do that yourself,
啊，如果你使用PyTorch 14，你不必自己这样做，
if you're going to implement it yourself then,
如果你打算自己实现它，
you might have a more difficult time.
你可能会遇到更困难的时候。
Um, yeah. So, I guess, yeah.
嗯，是的所以，我猜，是的。
Okay. All right, so, what do we get to. All right.
好的。好吧，那么，我们得到了什么。行。
So, let's talk about LSTMs and how they work in the- in the real world.
那么，让我们来谈谈LSTM以及它们如何在现实世界中发挥作用。
So, in the pretty recent past,
所以，在最近的过去，
2013-2015 um LSTM started achieving a lot of state of
2013-2015嗯LSTM开始实现很多状态
the art results on a variety of different tasks including for example,
艺术成果涉及各种不同的任务，例如，
handwriting recognition, speech recognition,
手写识别，语音识别，
machine translation, parsing, image captioning.
机器翻译，解析，图像字幕。
So, over this period,
所以，在此期间，
LSTMs became the dominant approach in a lot of
LSTM在很多方面成为主导方法
these application areas because they worked convincingly a lot better than vanilla RNNs.
这些应用领域因为它们比香草RNN更令人信服地工作。
However, today in 2019,
但是，今天在2019年，
things changed pretty fast in deep learning.
在深度学习中，事情变化很快。
So, other approaches for example,
所以，其他方法，例如，
transformers which you're going to learn about later in the class.
你将在课堂上学习的变形金刚。
Ah, in some of these application areas,
啊，在其中一些应用领域，
they seem to have become,
他们似乎已成为，
ah, the dominant approach.
啊，占主导地位的方法。
So, to look into this,
所以，看看这个，
I had a look at WMT which is a machine translation conference and
我看了一下WMT这是一个机器翻译会议
also competition where people submit their MT systems to be evaluated.
也是人们提交MT系统进行评估的竞争。
And I looked at the report,
我查看了报告，
the summary report for WMT 2016 and in this report,
WMT 2016和本报告的摘要报告，
I did a quick Ctrl+F,
我做了一个快速的Ctrl + F，
and I found the word RNN appeared 44 times.
我发现RNN这个词出现了44次。
So, it seems that most people entering this competition were building
所以，参加本次比赛的大多数人似乎都在建设中
their MT systems based on RNNs and in particular LSTMs.
他们的MT系统基于RNN，特别是LSTM。
And then I looked at the report from 2018,
然后我查看了2018年的报告，
just two years later and I found that the RNN,
两年后，我发现了RNN，
the word RNN only appeared nine times and the word transformer appeared 63 times,
RNN这个词只出现了9次，变压器这个词出现了63次，
and in fact the organizers noted that everyone,
事实上，组织者注意到每个人，
well, most people seem to using transformers now.
好吧，现在大多数人似乎都在使用变形金刚。
So um, this shows that things change pretty fast in deep learning.
所以，这表明在深度学习中事情变化很快。
The thing that was hot and new just a few years ago um,
几年前那个很热的东西，嗯，
is- is now being passed by perhaps by other kinds of approaches.
现在正在通过其他方式传递。
So, you're going to learn more about transformers
所以，你将学习更多关于变形金刚的知识
later but I guess that gives you a kind of
以后但我猜这会给你一种
idea of where LSTMs are currently in applications.
关于LSTM目前在哪些应用中的想法。
Okay. So, the second kind of RNN we're going to learn about is gated recurrent units.
好的。因此，我们将要了解的第二种RNN是门控循环单元。
So, these fortunately are simpler than LSTMs,
所以，幸运的是比LSTM更简单，
in fact that was the motivation for them being proposed.
事实上，这是他们被提议的动机。
They were proposed in 2014 as a way to try to retain
他们在2014年被提议作为一种尝试保留的方式
the strengths of LSTMs by getting rid of any unnecessary complexities.
通过消除任何不必要的复杂性，LSTM的优势。
So, in a GRU,
所以，在GRU中，
we don't have a cell state.
我们没有细胞状态。
We again just have a hidden state.
我们再次只是一个隐藏的状态。
But the thing it has in ah in common with LSTMs is that we're going to be
但它与LSTM的共同之处在于我们将会如此
using gates to control the flow of information.
使用门来控制信息流。
So, here are the equations for GRU.
所以，这是GRU的等式。
We start off with two gates.
我们从两个门开始。
So the first gate is called the update gate and this
所以第一个门叫做更新门，这个
controls what parts of the hidden states are going to be updated versus preserved.
控制隐藏状态的哪些部分将被更新而不是保留。
So, you can kind of view this as playing
所以，你可以把它看作是玩
the role of both the forget gate and the input gate in
忘记门和输入门的作用
the LSTM and it's computed in much the same way as the gates in the LSTM were.
LSTM和它的计算方式与LSTM中的门大致相同。
The second gate is called the reset gate rt,
第二个门称为复位门rt，
and this gate is controlling which parts of
这个门控制着哪个部分
the previous hidden state are going to be used to compute new contents.
先前的隐藏状态将用于计算新内容。
So, you can think of the- the reset gate as kind of selecting
因此，您可以将复位门视为一种选择
which parts of the previous hidden states are useful versus not useful.
以前隐藏状态的哪些部分是有用的而不是有用的。
So, it's going to discard some things and select some other things.
所以，它会丢弃一些东西并选择其他一些东西。
Okay. So, here's how those gates get used.
好的。那么，这就是这些门的使用方式。
Um, h tilde here.
嗯，这儿到了。
This is you can think of it as the new hidden state contents and what's
这是你可以把它想象成新的隐藏状态内容和什么
going on in that equation is that we are applying
继续这个等式是我们正在申请
the reset gate to the previous hidden state ht minus
复位门到前一个隐藏状态ht减去
one um and then putting all of that through some linear transformations and
一个嗯，然后把所有这些通过一些线性变换和
a tan H and then this gives us the new content
晒黑H然后这给了我们新的内容
which we want to write to the hidden cell.
我们想要写入隐藏的单元格。
And then lastly our new hidden cell is going to be a combination
然后最后我们的新隐藏单元将成为一个组合
of ah this new content and the previous hidden state.
这个新内容和以前的隐藏状态啊。
So, the important thing to notice here is that we have this one minus u and u term.
所以，这里要注意的重要一点是我们有这个减去你和你的术语。
So um, it's kind of like a balance right?
那么，这有点像平衡吗？
U is ah is setting the balance between
你是啊正在设置之间的平衡
preserving things from the previous hidden state versus writing new stuff.
保留以前隐藏状态的东西而不是写新东西。
So, whereas in the LSTM,
所以，在LSTM中，
those were two completely separate gates that could be whatever value.
那是两个完全独立的大门，可以是任何价值。
Here we have this constraint that U is being uh, balanced.
在这里，我们有这个约束，U是呃，平衡。
So, if you have more of one, you have to have less of the other.
所以，如果你有更多的，你必须少用另一个。
So, this is one way in which the creators of the GRU sought to make LSTMs more simple.
因此，这是GRU创作者寻求使LSTM更简单的一种方式。
Was by having a single gate play both of these roles.
是通过一个门来发挥这两个角色。
Okay. So, that's GRUs and I think it's a little less obvious just looking at it.
好的。所以，那是GRU，我认为仅仅看一下就不那么明显了。
Why GRUs help the vanishing gradients problem because there is no explicit ah memory
为什么GRU有助于消失渐变问题，因为没有明确的内存
cell, like there is in LSTMs.
细胞，就像LSTMs一样。
So, I think the way to look at this here is um GRUs,
所以，我认为在这里看待这个的方式是你的GRU，
you can view this as also being a solution to
你可以将其视为一种解决方案
the vanishing gradient problem because like LSTMs,
消失的梯度问题，因为像LSTM一样，
GRUs make it easier to retain information ah long-term.
GRU可以更容易地保留信息啊长期。
So, for example here,
所以，举个例子，
if the update gate ut is set to zero,
如果更新门ut设置为零，
then we're going to be ah keeping the hidden state the same on every step.
然后我们将会在每一步保持隐藏状态相同。
And again that's maybe not a good idea but at least that is a strategy you can easily
而且这可能不是一个好主意，但至少这是一个你可以轻松实现的策略
do in order to retain information over long distances.
这样做是为了保留长距离的信息。
So that's kind of like- like the same explanation of how GRUs make it
这就像GRU如何制作它一样
potentially easier for RNNs to retain information long-term.
RNN可能更容易长期保留信息。
Okay. So, we've learned about these two different types of RNNs. Yes.
好的。所以，我们已经了解了这两种不同类型的RNN。是。
[inaudible]
[听不见]
I think the question was,
我认为问题是，
if we view the two gates in the GRU, as being, uh,
如果我们在GRU中查看两个门，那么，呃，
a precise, um, analogy to the gates in the LSTM or are they more of a fuzzy analogy.
精确的，嗯，类似于LSTM中的门，或者它们更像是模糊的类比。
I'd say probably more of a fuzzy analogy
我想说的可能是模糊的比喻
because there are other changes going on in here, like,
因为这里还有其他变化，比如
for example, the fact that there's no separate, um,
例如，没有单独的，嗯，
memory cell, it means they're not performing exactly the same functions.
内存单元，这意味着它们没有执行完全相同的功能。
Yeah. Okay. So, we've learned about LSTMs and GRUs which are both,
是啊。好的。所以，我们已经了解了LSTM和GRU两者，
um, more complicated forms of RNNs,
嗯，更复杂的RNN形式，
more complicated than Vanilla RNNs.
比Vanilla RNN更复杂。
And they are both,
它们都是，
uh, more robust to the vanishing gradient problem.
呃，对消失的梯度问题更加强大。
So, um, it would be useful to know which of these should we be using in practice?
所以，嗯，了解我们应该在实践中使用哪些内容会很有用？
Which one is more successful,
哪一个更成功，
the LSTM or GRU?
LSTM还是GRU？
Uh, so, I- I did a little reading and it looks like researchers have
呃，所以，我 - 我做了一点阅读，看起来像研究人员
proposed a lot of different types of gated RNNs.
提出了许多不同类型的门控RNN。
So, it's not just GRUs and LSTMs,
所以，它不仅仅是GRU和LSTM，
there's many other papers with lots of other different variants.
还有很多其他论文有很多其他不同的变体。
Uh, but these are definitely the two that are most widely used.
呃，但这些绝对是最广泛使用的两个。
And, ah, you can probably say that the biggest difference between the two, um,
啊，你可以说两者之间最大的区别，嗯，
for sure is the fact that GRUs are simpler
可以肯定的是，GRU更简单
and quicker to compute and they have fewer parameters.
并且计算速度更快，参数更少。
So, this makes an actual practical difference to you as, uh,
所以，这对你来说是一个实际的实际差异，呃，
a deep learning practitioner because if you build your net based on GRUs,
一个深度学习的实践者，因为如果你基于GRU构建你的网络，
then it's gonna be faster to run forwards and,
那么前进的速度会更快，
you know, faster to train and so on.
你知道，训练更快，等等。
So, other than that, there appears to be
所以，除此之外，似乎还有
no very conclusive evidence that one of these LSTM or GRUs,
没有非常确凿的证据表明其中一个LSTM或GRU，
uh, is consistently outperforming the other on lots of different tasks.
呃，在很多不同的任务上始终优于对方。
Uh, it seems that often, uh,
呃，似乎经常，呃，
sometimes GRUs do perform as well as LSTMs,
有时GRU的表现与LSTM一样好，
but there are cases where one of them performs better than the other.
但有些情况下，其中一个表现优于另一个。
So, as a rule of thumb,
所以，根据经验，
it seems like LSTM is often a good default choice to start with, uh,
看起来LSTM通常是一个很好的默认选择，呃，
especially if your data has
特别是如果您的数据有
particularly long dependencies because there's evidence to think
特别长的依赖，因为有证据可以思考
that LSTMs might be slightly better at keeping information over very long distances.
LSTM可能在保持长距离信息方面略胜一筹。
And also, if you have a lot of training data,
而且，如果你有很多培训数据，
you might think that LSTMs are a better choice because they
您可能认为LSTM是更好的选择，因为它们
have more parameters which means that,
有更多的参数意味着，
um, maybe you need more train data to learn them.
嗯，也许你需要更多的火车数据来学习它们。
So, a rule of thumb is that maybe you want to start with LSTMs
所以，经验法则是你可能想要从LSTM开始
and if you're happy with their performance and you're
如果你对他们的表现感到满意，那你就是
happy with how long it takes to train, then you stick with that.
很高兴训练需要多长时间，然后你坚持下去。
But if you feel like you need it to be more efficient,
但如果你觉得你需要它更高效，
then maybe you should switch to GRUs and see how that goes with the performance
那么也许你应该切换到GRU，看看性能如何
and if it's faster. All right.
如果它更快行。
So, um, we've talked so far about how
那么，嗯，到目前为止我们已经谈过如何做了
the vanishing/exploding gradients are a problem that occur a lot in RNNs.
消失/爆炸的梯度是RNN中出现很多问题。
But, um, the question is,
但是，嗯，问题是，
is it only an RNN problem?
它只是一个RNN问题吗？
Does this occur in other kinds of neural networks as well?
这是否也发生在其他类型的神经网络中？
And the answer is,
答案是，
uh, no, it's not just an RNN problem.
呃，不，这不仅仅是一个RNN问题。
In fact, vanishing and exploding gradients are a
事实上，消失和爆炸的渐变是一个
pretty significant problem for
非常重要的问题
most neural architecture such as feed-forward and convolutional,
大多数神经结构，如前馈和卷积，
especially when they're deep.
特别是当他们很深的时候。
And this is a really serious problem because there's no point having
这是一个非常严重的问题，因为没有必要
a really cool neural architecture if you can't learn it efficiently because of the,
一个非常酷的神经架构如果你因为这个而无法有效地学习它，
uh, vanishing gradient problem.
呃，消失了梯度问题。
So, in particular, uh, in these feed-forward and convolutional networks, uh,
所以，特别是，呃，在这些前馈和卷积网络中，呃，
you often have a gradient becoming vanishingly
你经常会有一个渐渐消失的渐变
small over back-propagation, uh, because of the Chain Rule,
由于链规则，反向传播小，呃
because of this multiplying by
因为这个乘以
all these different intermediate gradients or
所有这些不同的中间梯度或
sometimes due to your choice of non-linearity function.
有时由于您选择了非线性函数。
So, if this happens, this means that your- the lower layers of your, let's say,
所以，如果发生这种情况，这意味着你 - 你的较低层，比方说，
convolutional or feed-forward network,
卷积或前馈网络，
they have a much smaller,
他们有一个小得多，
uh, gradient than the high levels.
呃，梯度比高水平。
And this means that they get changed very slowly during SGD.
这意味着他们在SGD期间变得非常缓慢。
So, this means that, overall,
所以，这意味着，整体而言，
your network is very slow to train because when you take updates,
您的网络训练非常慢，因为当您进行更新时，
then your lower layers are changing very slowly.
然后你的下层变化非常缓慢。
So, one solution, uh,
所以，一个解决方案，呃，
the kind of like a family of solutions that we've seen in
就像我们见过的一系列解决方案一样
recent years is that there's been lots of
最近几年有很多
proposals for new types of deep feed-forward or convolutional architectures.
关于新型深前馈或卷积架构的建议。
And what they do is, they add more direct connections in the network.
他们所做的是，他们在网络中添加更多直接连接。
And the- the idea,
而这个想法，
kind of as we talked about before,
我们之前谈过的那种，
is that if you add all of these direct connections between layers,
如果你在图层之间添加所有这些直接连接，
like maybe not just adjacent layers but further apart layers,
可能不仅仅是相邻的层，而是更远的层，
then it makes it much easier for the gradients to flow,
然后它使渐变更容易流动，
and you're going to find it easier to train your network overall.
而且你会发现整体训练网络更容易。
So, I'm going to show you some examples of these in
所以，我将向您展示一些这样的例子
particular because it's fairly likely you're going to
特别是因为你很可能会这样做
run into these kinds of architectures when you're doing your projects and reading papers.
当你在做项目和阅读论文时遇到这些架构。
So, one example is something called residual connections or,
所以，一个例子叫做残余连接，或者，
uh, the network itself is sometimes referred to as ResNet.
呃，网络本身有时也被称为ResNet。
And here we've got a figure from the related paper.
在这里，我们从相关论文中得到了一个数字。
So, what's going on in this diagram is that you have, uh,
那么，这张图中发生的是你有，呃，
the usual kind of you've got weight layer and
通常那种你有重量层和
a non-linearity which is ReLU, and another weight layer.
非线性，即ReLU，和另一个权重层。
So, if you regard that function as being f of x, ah,
所以，如果你认为那个函数是x的f，啊，
what they're doing is instead of just, ah,
他们正在做的不仅仅是，啊，
transforming x to f of x,
将x转换为x的f，
the- they're taking f of x plus x.
他们采用x加x的f。
So they're adding this identity skip connection where
所以他们在这里添加了这个身份跳过连接
the input x is skipped over those two layers and then,
在这两层上跳过输入x然后，
um, added to the output of the two layers.
嗯，添加到两层的输出中。
So, the reason why this is a good idea,
所以，这是一个好主意的原因，
uh, also known as skip connections,
呃，也称为跳过连接，
is that the identity connection is going to preserve information by default, right?
是标识连接默认保存信息，对吧？
So, if you imagine perhaps if you, um,
所以，如果你想象一下，如果你，嗯，
initialize your network and you
初始化您的网络和您
initialize your weight layers to have small random values,
初始化您的权重图层以获得小的随机值，
then if they're small and kind of close to zero,
那么如果它们很小并且接近零，
then you're going to have something like a noisy identity function, right?
然后你会有一个像嘈杂的身份功能，对吧？
So you're going to be preserving information by default through all of your layers.
因此，默认情况下，您将通过所有图层保留信息。
And if you have a very deep network,
如果你有一个非常深的网络，
that means that even often many,
这意味着即使经常很多，
um, many layers, you're still gonna have something like your original input.
嗯，很多层，你仍然会有类似你原始输入的东西。
So, uh, the- the people who wrote this paper, they show that, uh,
所以，呃，写这篇论文的人，他们表明，呃，
if you don't have something like skip connections then
如果你没有像跳过连接那样的话
actually you can find that deep layers- uh,
实际上你可以找到深层 - 呃，
deep networks perform worse on some tasks than shallow networks.
深度网络在某些任务上比浅层网络表现更差。
Not because they're not expressive enough,
不是因为他们没有足够的表现力，
but because they're too difficult to learn.
但是因为他们太难学了。
So, when you attempt to learn deep networks,
所以，当你尝试学习深层网络时，
it just doesn't learn effectively and you end up
它只是没有有效学习，你最终
getting worse performance in the shallow network.
在浅层网络中表现越来越差。
So, the people who wrote this paper,
所以，写这篇论文的人，
they show that when they add these skip connections,
他们表明，当他们添加这些跳过连接时，
then they made the deep networks, uh,
然后他们建立了深层网络，呃，
much more effective and they managed to get good performance.
更有效，他们设法获得了良好的表现。
Uh, so another example which kinda take this- this idea
呃，这是另一个例子，有点采取这个想法
further is something called dense connections or DenseNet.
进一步称为密集连接或密集网络。
And again, this was, uh,
再一次，这是，呃，
something proposed I think in a feed-forward or or convolutional setting.
我认为在前馈或卷积设置中提出了一些建议。
And, ah, it's just kind of the same as skip connections but except ,
而啊，它与跳过连接有点相似但除外
um, connects everything to everything.
嗯，把一切都连接到一切。
So, add more of these skip connections kind of
因此，添加更多这些跳过连接类型
from all layers to all layers and they showed that this,
从所有层到所有层，他们表明，
uh, performs even better.
呃，表现得更好。
And, uh, the last one I want to talk about which I don't have a picture
而且，呃，我想谈的最后一个我没有照片
for is something called highway connections.
因为是高速公路连接。
So, this is similar to the residual or skip connections.
因此，这类似于残余或跳过连接。
Ah, but the idea is that instead of just adding your x,
啊，但想法是，不只是添加你的x，
adding your identity, uh, connection,
添加你的身份，呃，连接，
the idea is that you're gonna have a gate that controls the balance between, um,
我的想法是，你将有一个控制平衡的大门，嗯，
adding the identity and computing, ah, the transformation.
添加身份和计算啊，转型。
So, instead of f of x plus x, you're gonna have, you know,
所以，你知道，你将拥有x加x的f，而不是
gate times f of x plus, you know,
你知道，x加的门时间f
one minus gate times x, something like that.
一减去门时间x，就像那样。
Um, so, this work was actually inspired by LSTMs,
嗯，这项工作实际上是受LSTM的启发，
but instead of applying it to a recurrent setting,
但不是将其应用于周期性设置，
they were seeking to apply it to a feed-forward setting.
他们正在寻求将其应用于前馈设置。
Okay. I'm gonna keep going for now.
好的。我现在要继续前进。
Um. So, overall the question was,
嗯。所以，问题总的来说是，
you know, how much uh,
你知道吗，呃，
vanishing and exploding gradients a problem outside of the setting of RNNs?
消失和爆炸梯度是RNN设置之外的问题？
And I think uh, the important takeaway is that it is a big problem
而且我想，呃，重要的一点是它是一个大问题
but you should notice that it is particularly a problem for RNNs.
但你应该注意到这对RNN来说尤其严重。
So, um, RNNs are particularly unstable and
所以，嗯，RNN特别不稳定
this is essentially due to the repeated multiplication by the same weight matrix.
这主要是由于重复乘以相同的权重矩阵。
If you remember from last time, um,
如果你记得上次，嗯，
the characteristic thing about RNNs that makes them recurrent is
关于RNNs的特征性事件使它们反复发作
the fact that you are applying the same weight matrix over and over again.
事实上你一遍又一遍地应用相同的权重矩阵。
So, this is actually the core reason
所以，这实际上是核心原因
why they are so prone to the vanishing and exploding gradients,
为什么他们如此倾向于消失和爆炸的渐变，
and ah, you can see some more information about that in the paper.
啊，你可以在论文中看到更多关于它的信息。
Okay. So, I know there's been a lot of dense information today,
好的。所以，我知道今天有很多密集的信息，
a lot of um, lot of notation.
很多嗯，很多符号。
So, here's a recap, if I've lost you at any point.
所以，这是一个回顾，如果我在任何时候都失去了你。
Now's a good time to jump back in because it's gonna
现在是跳回来的好时机，因为它会
get a little easier to understand perhaps.
或许更容易理解。
So, okay, recap. What have we learned about today?
所以，好的，回顾一下。我们今天学到了什么？
Um, the first thing we learned about was the vanishing gradient problem.
嗯，我们学到的第一件事就是消失的梯度问题。
We learned uh, what it is.
我们学到了呃，它是什么。
We learned why it happens and we saw why it's bad for RNNs,
我们了解了它为什么会发生，我们看到了为什么它对RNN不利，
for example, RNN language models.
例如，RNN语言模型。
Ah, and we also learned about LSTMs and GRUs which are
啊，我们也了解了LSTM和GRU
more complicated RNNs and they use gates to control the flow of information.
更复杂的RNN，他们使用门来控制信息流。
And by doing that, they are more resilient to the vanishing gradient problem.
通过这样做，他们对消失的梯度问题更具弹性。
Okay. So, if the remainder of this lecture,
好的。那么，如果本讲座的其余部分，
I think we've got about 20 minutes left,
我想我们还剩下大约20分钟，
ah, we're going to be learning about two more advanced type of RNNs.
啊，我们将学习两种更先进的RNN。
So, the first one is bidirectional RNNs and that's all
所以，第一个是双向RNN，就是这样
about information flowing left to right and right to left.
关于从左到右流动的信息。
And then we're also going to learn about
然后我们也将学习
multi-layer RNNs which is when you apply multiple RNNs on top of each other.
多层RNN，当您将多个RNN应用于彼此之上时。
So, I'd say that both of these are pretty simple conceptually.
所以，我会说这两个在概念上都非常简单。
Um, so it shouldn't be too hard to understand.
嗯，所以不应该太难理解。
All right, so let's start with bidirectional RNNs.
好的，让我们从双向RNN开始吧。
Um, this is a picture which you saw at the end of last lecture.
嗯，这是你在上次讲座结束时看到的一张照片。
So, if you remember,
所以，如果你还记得，
sentiment classification is the task when you have
情绪分类是你的任务
some kind of input sentence such as the movie was
某种输入句子如电影是
terribly exciting and you want to classify this as a positive or negative sentiment.
非常令人兴奋，你想把它归类为积极或消极的情绪。
So, in this example, it should be seen as positive sentiment.
因此，在这个例子中，它应被视为积极的情绪。
So, um, this is an example of how you might try to
所以，嗯，这是你可能尝试的一个例子
solve sentiment classification using a fairly simple RNN model.
使用相当简单的RNN模型解决情绪分类。
Ah, here we're using the RNN as a kind of encoder of
啊，我们在这里使用RNN作为一种编码器
the sentence and the hidden states represent the sentence.
句子和隐藏状态代表句子。
And we'll do some kind of combination of the hidden states to compute uh,
我们会做一些隐藏状态的组合来计算呃，
what we think the sentiment is.
我们认为情绪是什么。
So, my question is, if we look at let's say,
所以，我的问题是，如果我们看看，让我们说，
the hidden state that corresponds to the word terribly and we're regarding
与这个词相对应的隐藏状态，我们正在考虑
this hidden state as a representation of the word
这个隐藏的状态作为这个词的表示
terribly in the context of the sentence.
非常在句子的背景下。
So, for this reason we- we sometimes call hidden states in this kind of situation
因此，出于这个原因，我们有时会在这种情况下调用隐藏状态
a contextual representation because the idea is that it's
一个上下文表示，因为这个想法就是它
a representation of the word terribly in the context of the sentence.
在句子的语境中非常表达这个词。
So, thing to think about here is that this contextual representation,
所以，在这里考虑的是这个上下文表示，
it only contains information about the left context.
它只包含有关左上下文的信息。
So, for terribly, the left context is the words um,
所以，非常，左边的上下文是单词um，
the movie was and this hidden state the one that's got
电影是，这个隐藏的状态是有的
a blue box around it has only seen information to the left.
它周围的蓝框只能看到左边的信息。
It hasn't seen the information of the words exciting or exclamation mark.
它没有看到令人兴奋或感叹号的信息。
So, what we're asking is what about the right context?
那么，我们要问的是正确的背景呢？
The right context of terribly is- is what exciting and the exclamation mark.
正确的背景是令人兴奋和惊叹号。
And do we think that the right context is useful here?
我们认为正确的背景在这里有用吗？
Do we think that this is something we want to know about?
我们是否认为这是我们想知道的事情？
And I would argue that in this example,
我会争辩说，在这个例子中，
it is actually kind of important because we've got the phrase terribly exciting.
它实际上很重要，因为我们有这句话非常令人兴奋。
And if you look at the word terribly in isolation,
如果你孤立地看着这个词，
terrible or terribly usually means something bad, right?
可怕或非常通常意味着坏事，对吧？
But terribly exciting, you can mean something good because it just means very exciting.
但非常令人兴奋，你可以说一些好东西，因为它只是意味着非常令人兴奋。
So, if you know about the right context,
所以，如果你了解正确的背景，
the word exciting then this might quite significantly
这个词令人兴奋，那么这可能非常显着
modify your perception of the meaning of the word
修改你对这个词含义的看法
terribly in the context of the sentence.
非常在句子的背景下。
And especially given that we're trying to do sentiment classification,
特别考虑到我们正在尝试进行情绪分类，
this is- this is kind of important.
这是 - 这很重要。
So this motivates why you might want to have information
所以这就激发了为什么你可能想要获得信息
from both the left and the right when you're making your representations.
当您进行陈述时，从左侧和右侧开始。
Ah, if when you were a kid,
啊，如果你小时候，
your parents told you to look both ways before you cross the street.
你的父母告诉你在过马路之前要两面看。
You might regard it as the same kind of idea that there's
你可能会认为它是同一种想法
useful information to the left and the right that
左侧和右侧的有用信息
you'd like to know about ah, before you do anything.
在你做任何事之前，你想知道啊。
Okay. So that's the motivation and um,
好的。这就是动力和嗯，
here is how a bidirectional RNN might work in practice.
这里是双向RNN如何在实践中发挥作用。
I have a kind of accidentally festive color scheme here.
我这里有一种偶然的节日配色方案。
And so the idea is that you have two RNNs going on.
所以我们的想法是你有两个RNN正在进行中。
You have the forward RNN as before that encodes the sentence left to right.
你有前面的RNN，从左到右编码句子。
And then separately, you also have a backwards RNN.
然后另外，你还有一个向后的RNN。
And this has completely separate weights to the forward RNN.
并且这与前向RNN具有完全独立的权重。
So, the backward RNN is just doing the same thing
因此，后向RNN正在做同样的事情
except that it's encoding the sequence from right to left.
除了它从右到左编码序列。
So, each of the hidden states is computed based on the one to the right.
因此，每个隐藏状态都是基于右边的一个计算的。
And then finally, you just take the hidden states from
然后最后，你只需要隐藏状态
the two RNNs and then you concatenate them together and you've got your uh,
两个RNN，然后你把它们连接在一起，你就得到了你的呃，
your final kind of representations.
你的最后一种陈述。
So, in particular, if we now think about
所以，特别是，如果我们现在考虑一下
this contextual representation of the word terribly in the context,
这个词在语境中非常可见，
um, this- this vector has information from both the left and the right, right?
嗯，这个 - 这个向量有来自左边和右边的信息，对吧？
Because you had the forwards and backwards RNNs that
因为你有前向和后向的RNN
respectively had information from both left and right.
分别有左右两侧的信息。
So the idea is that these concatenated hidden states,
所以这个想法是这些连接的隐藏状态，
those can be regarded as kind of like the outputs of the bidirectional RNN.
那些可以被视为类似于双向RNN的输出。
Like if you're going to use these hidden states for
就像你要使用这些隐藏状态一样
any kind of further computation, then ah,
任何进一步的计算，然后啊，
it's these concatenated hidden states that you are going to be
这些是你将要成为的连锁隐藏状态
passing on to the next part of the network.
传递到网络的下一部分。
Um, here- here are the equations that just say the same thing.
嗯，这里 - 这里是说同样的事情的方程式。
So, you have your forward RNN and here we've got ah,
所以，你有你的前进RNN，在这里我们有啊，
a notation that you might not have seen before
你可能以前没见过的符号
this kind of notation where it says RNN and then in brackets,
这种符号表示RNN，然后在括号中，
the previous hidden state and the input that's simply saying that you know,
以前隐藏的状态和输入只是说你知道，
HT is computed from the previous hidden state and the input.
HT是根据先前的隐藏状态和输入计算的。
And RNN forward could be a vanilla or a GRU or an LSTM.
RNN转发可以是香草或GRU或LSTM。
It doesn't really matter, we're looking at it abstractly.
这并不重要，我们正在抽象地看待它。
So, you have these two separate RNNs,
所以，你有这两个独立的RNN，
RNN forwards and RNN backwards and generally, these have separate weights.
RNN向后转发和RNN向后并且通常，它们具有单独的权重。
Although I have seen some papers where they have shared weights.
虽然我看过一些他们有共同权重的论文。
So, it seems that sometimes that does work better,
所以，有时似乎确实有效，
perhaps maybe when you have enough training data.
也许当你有足够的训练数据时。
And then finally, we regard these concatenated hidden states which you might just
最后，我们将这些连接的隐藏状态视为您可能只是
notice ht as being like the hidden state of the bidirectional RNN.
请注意，就像双向RNN的隐藏状态一样。
So, um, the previous diagram is pretty unwieldy.
那么，嗯，上面的图表非常笨拙。
So here's a simplified diagram.
所以这是一个简化的图表。
And this is probably the only kind of diagram you're going to
这可能是你要去的唯一一种图表
see from now on to denote bidirectional RNNs.
从现在开始看，表示双向RNN。
Um, so, what we've done here is you've just
嗯，所以，我们在这里所做的就是你
made all of the horizontal arrows go left and right ah,
使所有的水平箭头左右啊，
to represent that this is a bidirectional RNN.
表示这是双向RNN。
So, the other thing you should assume is that the hidden states depicted here, you know,
所以，你应该假设的另一件事是这里描述的隐藏状态，你知道，
these red- red trying- red rectangles with the dots.
这些带有圆点的红红色试图红色矩形。
You can assume that those are the concatenated forwards,
你可以假设那些是连接的前锋，
backwards hidden states from the bidirectional RNN.
从双向RNN向后隐藏的状态。
[inaudible]
[听不见]
Okay. So the question is, um,
好的。所以问题是，嗯，
would you train your forwards and backwards RNNs kind of separately,
你会分别训练你的前锋和后退RNN吗？
um, on some kind of task and then
嗯，在某种任务上，然后
maybe concatenate them together once they're separately trained networks,
一旦他们被分别训练的网络，也许可以将它们连接在一起，
or would you train them all together?
或者你会一起训练他们吗？
Um, it seems to me that it's much more common to train them together,
嗯，在我看来，将它们训练在一起更为常见，
but I don- I don't think I've heard of anyone training them separately.
但是我 - 我不认为我听说过有人单独训练它们。
Uh, so yeah, it seems like the standard practice is usually
呃，所以是的，似乎通常是标准做法
to train them together. Does that make sense?
一起训练他们。那有意义吗？
[inaudible].
[听不见的。
So, let's suppose that we were trying to build
所以，让我们假设我们正在努力建立
a sentiment classification system using the bidirectional RNN.
使用双向RNN的情绪分类系统。
Then what you do, which maybe I should have pictured but I didn't have space, is uh,
然后你做了什么，也许我应该想象，但我没有空间，是呃，
you would do the same thing that you were doing with the unidirectional RNN, uh,
你会做与单向RNN一样的事情，呃，
which was, let's say an element y is min or max,
也就是说，元素y是min或max，
um, to get your sentence encoding.
嗯，得到你的句子编码。
Maybe you just do that but over the concatenated, um, n states.
也许你只是这样做，但在连接的，嗯，n州。
Okay. So, an important thing to note is that, uh,
好的。所以，需要注意的一点是，呃，
when talking about applying bidirectional RNNs,
在谈论应用双向RNN时，
we've assumed that we actually have access to the entire input sequence.
我们假设我们实际上可以访问整个输入序列。
So, we assume that we have the full sentence,
所以，我们假设我们有完整的句子，
uh, the movie was very exciting, and,
呃，这部电影很精彩，而且，
uh, that, that was a necessary assumption in order to
呃，那是一个必要的假设
be able to run the forwards and the backwards RNN, right?
能够运行前进和后退RNN，对吗？
Um, so there are some situations where you can't assume this.
嗯，所以在某些情况下你不能假设这一点。
Like, for example, in Language Modeling,
例如，在语言建模中，
you only have access to the left context kind of by definition of the task.
根据任务的定义，您只能访问左上下文类型。
You only know the words that have come so far.
你只知道到目前为止所说的话。
You don't know what's coming next.
你不知道接下来会发生什么。
So, you can't use a bidirectional RNN, uh,
所以，你不能使用双向RNN，呃，
to do Language Modeling, uh,
做语言建模，呃，
in the way that we've depicted here because uh,
就像我们在这里描绘的那样，因为呃，
you don't have the full sequence.
你没有完整的序列。
However, if you do have access to the entire sequence.
但是，如果您确实可以访问整个序列。
Uh, so, for example, if you're doing any kind of encoding
呃，所以，例如，如果您正在进行任何类型的编码
similar to the sentiment example,
类似于情绪的例子，
uh, then bidirectionally- bidirectionality is pretty powerful.
呃，那么双向 - 双向性非常强大。
And you should probably regard it as a good thing to do by default uh,
而你应该认为默认情况下这是一件好事呃，
because it turns out that getting this information from
因为事实证明从中获取此信息
both the left and the right, uh,
左边和右边，呃，
makes it a lot easier to learn these more useful contextual representations.
这使得学习这些更有用的上下文表示变得更加容易。
So, in particular, as a preview of
因此，特别是作为预览
something you're going to learn about later in the class, uh,
你将在课堂上学到的东西，呃，
there's a model called BERT, B-E-R-T,
有一个名为BERT，BERT的模型，
and that stands for Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers.
这代表变形金刚的双向编码器表示。
And this is a pretty recently.
这是最近的一个。
Like, a few months ago, uh, proposed system,
就像，几个月前，呃，建议的系统，
and it's this pre-trained contextual representation system.
这是这种预先训练的语境表达系统。
Um, and it's heavily reliant on the idea of bidirectionality.
嗯，它严重依赖双向性的想法。
It turns out that the bidirectional, uh,
事实证明是双向的，呃，
nature of BERT is pretty important to its success.
BERT的本质对其成功非常重要。
So, you're gonna learn more about that later,
那么，你以后会更多地了解它，
but that's just an example of how bidirectionality can give you much
但这只是双向性如何给你带来更多的一个例子
more uh, powerful contextual representations.
更呃，强大的语境表征。
Okay. So the last thing we're going to talk about today is multi-layer RNNs.
好的。所以我们今天要讨论的最后一件事是多层RNN。
Uh, so you could regard RNNs as already being deep
呃，所以你可以认为RNN已经很深了
in some sense because you've already unrolled them over potentially very many timesteps,
从某种意义上讲，因为你已经将它们展开了非常多的时间步，
and you could regard that as a kind of depth, right?
你可以把它视为一种深度，对吧？
But there's another way that RNNs could be deep.
但是还有另一种方式可以让RNN深入人心。
So, for example, if you applied multiple RNNs kind of one after another,
因此，例如，如果您一个接一个地应用多个RNN，
then this would be a different way to make your RNN deep,
那么这将是让你的RNN深入的另一种方式，
and this is the idea between, uh,
这是呃之间的想法，呃，
behind a multi-layer RNN.
在多层RNN背后。
So, the reason why you would want to do this is because uh,
那么，你想要这样做的原因是因为呃，
this might allow the network to compute more complex representations.
这可能允许网络计算更复杂的表示。
So, this is the logic betwe- behind deep networks in general.
因此，这是深层网络背后的逻辑。
So, if you're familiar with the idea of why
所以，如果你熟悉为什么这么做的话
deeper is better for let's say convolutional networks,
更糟糕的是让我们说卷积网络，
then this is kind of the same logic.
那么这是一种相同的逻辑。
It's saying that, uh, your lower RNNs might be computing lower-level features like,
它说，呃，你的较低RNN可能正在计算低级功能，如，
let's suppose maybe it's keeping track of syntax,
让我们假设它可能跟踪语法，
and your higher  level RNN's gonna compute higher-level features like maybe semantics.
而你的更高级别的RNN将计算更高级别的功能，例如语义。
And a note on terminology, these are sometimes called stacked RNNs.
关于术语的注释，这些有时被称为堆叠RNN。
So, this works much as you'd imagine.
所以，这就像你想象的那样有效。
So here's an example of how a multi-layer RNN might work.
所以这是一个多层RNN如何工作的例子。
Uh, if it's three layers.
呃，如果它是三层。
So this is a unidirectional RNN,
所以这是一个单向的RNN，
but it could be bidirectional,
但它可能是双向的，
um, If you have access to the entire input sequence.
嗯，如果您可以访问整个输入序列。
So, I guess the, the main thing is that the hidden states from one RNN layer are going to
所以，我猜，主要是来自一个RNN层的隐藏状态
be used as the inputs to the RNN layer that's coming next.
用作下一个RNN层的输入。
Um, any questions on this?
嗯，有什么问题吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
[inaudible].
[听不见的。
That's a great question. So the question I think it's about the order of computation.
这是一个很好的问题。所以我认为这是关于计算顺序的问题。
What order will you compute all of these hidden states in?
您将以什么顺序计算所有这些隐藏状态？
I suppose there's some flexibility, right?
我想有一些灵活性，对吧？
But you could compute all of the step one ones,
但你可以计算所有第一步，
like all of the V ones and then all of the movie ones,
像所有的V，然后所有的电影，
or you could do all of RNN layer one and then all of RNN layer two.
或者你可以做所有RNN第一层，然后是RNN第二层。
So, it's- I think that, um, when you- you know,
所以，我认为，嗯，当你 - 你知道的时候，
call the PyTorch function to do a multi-layer RNN,
调用PyTorch函数来做一个多层RNN，
it will do all of RNN layer one, then two, then three.
它将完成所有RNN第一层，然后是第二层，然后是第三层。
That's what I think happens.
这就是我认为发生的事情。
But it seems like logically,
但似乎逻辑上，
there's no reason why you couldn't do it the other way.
你无法以其他方式做到这一点。
Yep?  [inaudible].
是的？ [听不见的。
Yes, yes. That's a great point as well.
是的是的。这也是一个很好的观点。
Um, so uh, someone pointed out that if they were bidirectional,
嗯，所以，有人指出，如果它们是双向的，
then you no longer have that flexibility.
然后你不再具有这种灵活性。
You would have to do all of layer one before layer two.
您必须在第二层之前完成第一层的所有操作。
Yeah, good point. Anyone else?
是的，好的一点。还有谁？
Okay. Uh, so mostly RNNs in practice,
好的。呃，实际上大部分是RNN，
um, this tends to perform pretty well,
嗯，这往往表现得很好，
uh, in that when I look at, um,
呃，当我看着，嗯，
RNN-based systems that are doing very well on some kind of task,
基于RNN的系统在某种任务上做得非常好，
they usually are some kind of multi-layer RNN, um,
他们通常是某种多层RNN，嗯，
but they certainly aren't as deep as
但他们肯定没有那么深
the deep convolutional or feed-forward networks you might have seen in,
您可能已经看过的深度卷积或前馈网络，
for example, image tasks.
例如，图像任务。
So whereas, you know, very deep convolutional networks,
所以，你知道，非常深的卷积网络，
I think hundreds of layers now, um,
我想现在有数百层，嗯，
you certainly aren't getting RNNs that are that deep.
你肯定没有得到那么深的RNN。
So, for example, um,
所以，例如，嗯，
in this paper from, uh, Google, uh,
在本文中，呃，Google，呃，
they're doing this kind of large hyperparameter search for
他们正在进行这种大型超参数搜索
neural machine translation to find which kinds of hyperparameters work well for NMT.
神经机器翻译找到哪种超参数适用于NMT。
And in this paper, they found that um,
在本文中，他们发现嗯，
two to four layers was best for the encoder RNN,
两到四层最适合编码器RNN，
and four layers was best for the decoder RNN.
四层最适合解码器RNN。
Uh, you'll find out more about what encoder and decoder mean next time.
呃，你会发现下一次编码器和解码器的含义。
Um, but those are fairly small numbers.
嗯，但那些数字相当小。
Although they did find that if you add these skip
虽然他们确实发现如果你添加这些跳过
connections or these dense connections, um,
连接或这些密集的连接，嗯，
then it makes it much easier to learn some even deeper RNNs more effectively,
那么它可以更容易地更有效地学习更深层次的RNN，
like, maybe up to eight layers,
喜欢，可能多达八层，
but these certainly aren'tx  hundreds of layers deep.
但这些肯定不会超过数百层。
And one of the reasons why, uh,
还有一个原因，呃，
RNNs don't tend to be nearly as deep as these other kinds of networks,
RNN往往不如其他类型的网络那么深，
is that because as we commented before,
是因为我们之前评论过，
RNNs have to be computed, uh,
必须计算RNN，呃，
sequentially; they can't be computed in parallel.
顺序;它们无法并行计算。
This means that they're pretty expensive to compute.
这意味着它们的计算成本非常高。
If you have this depth in like, two-dimensions,
如果你有这样的深度，像二维，
you have the depth over the timesteps and then the depth over the RNN layer is two,
你有时间步长的深度，然后RNN层的深度是两个，
then it beco- it becomes very,
然后它变得非常，
very expensive to compute these, these RNNs.
这些RNN非常昂贵。
So, that's another reason why they don't get very deep.
所以，这是他们不深入的另一个原因。
Uh, so again, we just mentioned transformers.
呃，我们再次提到变形金刚。
Uh, you gonna learn about transformers later.
呃，你以后会学习变形金刚。
But these, it seems, um,
但是，似乎这些，嗯，
can be deeper fro- from what I can tell of,
可以更深入地从我所知道的，
of what people are using these days.
人们现在使用的是什么
Transformer-based networks can be pretty deep.
基于变压器的网络可能非常深入。
So, uh, but for example,
所以，呃，但是，例如，
there's a 24-layer version and a 12-layer version, um,
有一个24层版本和一个12层版本，嗯，
and admittedly, that was trained by Google,
不可否认，这是由Google培训的，
and they have a lot of computational power.
他们有很多计算能力。
Um, but I think part of the reason why
嗯，但我认为部分原因
these transformer-based networks can be quite deep,
这些基于变压器的网络可以很深，
is that they have a lot of these skipping like connections.
是他们有很多这样的跳过连接。
In fact, the whole um,
事实上，整个嗯，
innovation of transformers is that they're built on a lot of, kind of,
变形金刚的创新是它们建立在很多种类的基础之上，
skip connections. Okay, any questions?
跳过连接。好的，有什么问题吗？
We're almost done. Okay. All right.
我们差不多完成了。好的。行。
So, uh, here's a summary of what we've learned today.
所以，呃，这是我们今天学到的东西的总结。
I know it's been a lot of information.
我知道这是很多信息。
Um, but I think here are four practical takeaways from today that, uh,
嗯，但我认为这是今天的四个实际要点，呃，
are probably useful to you in your projects,
对你的项目可能有用，
even if you, um,
即使你，嗯，
uh, even if you
呃，即使你
didn't find them very interesting in themselves they're probably pretty useful.
没发现它们本身很有趣，它们可能非常有用。
So, the first one is that LSTMs are very powerful.
所以，第一个是LSTM非常强大。
They're certainly a lot powerful than,
他们肯定比很强大，
uh, more powerful than Vanila RNNs.
呃，比Vanila RNN更强大。
Um, GRUs are also more powerful than, uh, Vanila RNNs.
嗯，GRU也比Vanila RNN更强大。
Uh, and the only difference that is consistently the
呃，唯一的区别是一贯的
same is that GRUs are faster than LSTMs.
同样是GRU比LSTM更快。
The next one is that you should probably clip your gradients,
下一个是你应该剪辑你的渐变，
because if you don't clip your gradients,
因为如果你没有剪辑你的渐变，
you're in danger of walking off cliffs and then ending up with NaNs in your model.
你有走出悬崖然后在模型中使用NaNs的危险。
Uh, the next tip is that bidirectionality is useful if you can apply it.
呃，下一个提示是，如果您可以应用双向性，那么它很有用。
And, basically, anytime when you have access to the entire input sequence,
而且，基本上，只要您有权访问整个输入序列，
you can apply bidirectionality,
你可以申请双向性，
so you should probably do that by default.
所以你应该默认这样做。
And then the last tip is that multi-layer RNNs are pretty powerful.
然后最后一个提示是多层RNN非常强大。
And again, you should probably do that if you,
再说一遍，如果你，你应该这样做
uh, have enough computational power to do so.
呃，有足够的计算能力来做到这一点。
But if you're going to make your multi-layer RNN pretty deep,
但是如果你要让你的多层RNN相当深，
then you might need skip connections.
那么你可能需要跳过连接。
All right. Thanks [NOISE].
行。谢谢[NOISE]。